我曾经对《死亡搁浅》持非常怀疑的态度 甚至一度批评过它
I was very skeptical and even critical of Death Stranding going into it.
我曾对这款游戏各种浮夸的预告与故意模糊游戏内容表示强烈谴责
I bashed it for pretentious marketing intentionally vague explanations of gameplay
我也曾强烈批评小岛秀夫他自己竟无法
and I heavily criticized Kojima himself for his seeming inability
简明扼要地阐明这到底是一款什么样的游戏
to concisely or even coherently define what Death Stranding was.
乍一看它就是一款完全靠“小岛秀夫”这名字为卖点的游戏
It seemed to be a game sold entirely on the name of its creator
这点实际上与他自己的信念相悖
which is actually antithetical to Kojima's own beliefs
至少是与他在2014年发布PT时的信念相悖
or at least the beliefs that he described in 2014 with PT.
当年他在PlayStation商店发布PT这款试玩版的时候
You see when he released the Playable Teaser onto the PlayStation Store as a free demo,
他刻意隐去了他的姓名 他的工作室 他的发行商名称
he intentionally hid his name, his studio and his publisher's branding
游戏本身的宣发材料中丝毫找不到他的踪迹
from every piece of the demo's promotional materials.
据他说 让玩家不知道游戏制作人是谁 玩家就可以不受任何预设的影响
And according to him he did this so that players would be free of any presuppositions
they may have going into a title knowing who created it.
换句话说 他希望玩家能享受PT这款游戏本身
In other words, he wanted players to enjoy PT for what it was,
而不是冲着游戏制作人去的
not for who it was created by.
但到了《死亡搁浅》这里情况就不一样了
However this is not so for Death Stranding.
《死亡搁浅》完全就是以小岛秀夫的名字和他天才般的游戏制作能力为卖点的
Death Stranding was sold entirely
on Kojima's name and the brilliance with which he crafts his games.
这是一个实实在在的重要转变 不容忽视
This is an important and remarkable shift in the pure sense of the word,
and it's one that cannot be overlooked.
坦率地讲 这改变了我们所有人游玩这款游戏时的看法
This frankly changes the way that we all will look and play the game
因为小岛自己就改变了他向我们展示游戏的方式
because Kojima himself is changing the way that he presents it to us.
当然 当一个人的名字能和这款游戏紧紧联系在一起时
Now of course it goes without saying but when any individual is tied so inextricably to a game,
玩家就不得不预先戴上有色眼镜来看待它了
you have to look at it through that lens.
所以我决定作为一个公正的观察者 甚至作为一个评论家来玩玩《死亡搁浅》
And so I decided to play Death Stranding as an impartial observer or even as a critic.
我从来都不是小岛的粉丝
I am by no means a fanboy of Kojima
也从来没真正玩过他的任何其他游戏
and I have never actually played to completion any of his other games.
不过我在准备这期视频之前的确玩了大概五小时的《合金装备V 幻痛》
Although I did play roughly 5 hours of Metal Gear Solid V in preparation for this video.
如果你关注了我这个频道 可能知道我在开始时并不是《死亡搁浅》的粉丝
Now if you followed this channel you'll know
that I was not a fan of Death Stranding when I began.
实际上我花了大概八小时才开始对游戏有一点点的喜欢
In fact it took roughly 8 hours for it to click
and for me to begin enjoying it even in the least.
我甚至做了一期视频痛批了游戏的前两小时内容
I even made a video where I roasted the first 2 hours of the game,
“痛批前两小时内容”的视频链接在下方
原视频在字幕制作时YouTube差评率接近1/4
弄得不少游戏粉丝不开心
much to the chagrin of the game's fans.
然而过了8小时候 也就是我玩到游戏中期的时候
However after this 8 hour mark in other words once I got to the mid-game,
我开始期待能早点下课回家玩这款游戏了
I started looking forward to playing the game when I got back from classes.
游戏也开始变成了我的解压玩具
And it actually became my relaxation outlet.
不停爬山送快递真的特别解压
Hiking and delivering packages was effectively stress-relief.
简单来说 《死亡搁浅》于我而言就像垃圾食品一样
Simply put, Death Stranding for me is a junk-food game.
没啥营养但又吃个没完
It's easy to consume nearly impossible to fathom
管不住嘴 可劲吃 好像多有营养一样
and it leaves you feeling as though you must consume more to gain any sustenance whatsoever
可惜实际上干货并没有多少
even though there isn't actually much there.
不过没有游戏是完美的 《死亡搁浅》也不例外
Now no game is perfect, Death Stranding included.
这款游戏在为整个行业引入一些新奇想法的同时
And while introducing some interesting ideas to the industry,
的确存在着一些严重缺陷
it does have some serious flaws.
这期视频里我将非常诚恳地告诉大家
Now I'm going to be very honest in this video,
我热爱这款游戏 我认为很多对其表示批评的人都有合理的观点
I'm a fan of the game and I think most people who are critical of it have reasonable points
但《死亡搁浅》也有做得好的地方
but there are also things that Death Stranding does well.
我们将在这期视频中讨论所有这些内容
And we'll discuss all of these things in this video.
但重点在于 如果我们不能诚恳面对游戏的缺点
But the point is if we're not honest about the game's shortcomings
就无法让小岛秀夫继续改进他的下一款游戏
we can't help Kojima with whatever his next game is.
而只要你玩过《死亡搁浅》
And if you've played Death Stranding for any length of time
你就应该或多或少知道游戏的种种缺点
you should be aware of some of the plethora of issues.
我只是想重申一下 虽然我对游戏中许多设计选择感觉非常矛盾
And I just want to reiterate that
while I am very conflicted on many of the design choices made here
但我将利用视频大部分时间来解释游戏中的所有问题
and I am going to spend most of this video explaining all of the problems with the game.
总的来说 我还是非常享受游玩《死亡搁浅》的
I really did enjoy my time with Death Stranding on the whole.
让我一言以蔽之的话
If I had to describe the game concisely
我会把它评价为一款重复的 放松的 不复杂的游戏
I would say that it's a repetitive relaxing and uncomplicated game
以其模棱两可的叙事
that is overly reliant on ambiguous storytelling
光荣成为了小岛秀夫诡异的导演手法笔下的受害者
and falls victim to some very bizarre directorial decisions at the hands of Hideo Kojima,
而小岛本人的名字也快和游戏本身绑定起来了
a man so closely tied to Death Stranding that he and the game are inextricably tied,
毕竟他自己都说了那么多
mostly due to his own statements saying as much.
译注：译者《死亡搁浅》PS4白金
另外我也有必要告知大家我做这期视频前都做了哪些功课
It's also probably important that I mentioned my qualifications for making this video.
我在两台PS4上总共大约游玩了100小时的《死亡搁浅》
I've put in well over a hundred hours into Death Stranding on two separate PS4s,
一台Slim 一台Pro 从而了解游戏在技术层面的表现如何
a Slim and a Pro, to get an idea of what this game can do technically,
稍后会稍作提及
something will touch on lightly later.
我读过了所有的邮件 完成了所有的高级配送订单
I read all of the Emails, completed all of the premium deliveries,
杀过所有种类的BT 开过所有种类的车 和所有的名人有过对话
fought all of the BTs, drove all of the vehicles, talked to every celebrity,
摇匀了BB的脑浆 集齐了所有存储芯片
shook all the babies, hunted down the memory chips,
所有设施的连接等级达到最高 探索了地图的所有地方 在此基础上
five-star the locations, explored the whole map and after all of that,
我可以自信地说 《死亡搁浅》这款游戏是迄今为止
I can say confidently the Death Stranding is by far,
我这辈子玩过的最讽刺的游戏
the most ironic game that I have ever played in my life.
游戏宣传说是一种全新的游戏类型
You see the game was advertised as a new genre of game,
内容注重于人的积极性 与连接全世界的人们
something that would focus on positivity and connecting people from all over the world.
但它却成为了过去十年 甚至整个游戏史上分歧最严重的游戏之一
But instead it's become one of the most divisive games of the last decade, maybe of all time.
有些人认为游戏空洞无聊
Some will say that the world is empty boring,
游玩内容重复 剧情糟糕
and the gameplay is repetitive and the writing is terrible.
但同时还有人认为《死亡搁浅》是一款专注于人与人之间的连接与实现
While others will say the Death Stranding is a triumph,
a game that try something new and succeeds,
并成功吃到了螃蟹的游戏
a game focused on connections and fulfillment.
但有意思的是 大家说的基本都在理
And the amazing thing is that everyone here is kind of right.
听上去有点扯 仿佛听君一席话 如听一席话
And I know that sounds like an oxymoron or completely nonsensical
但我认为我能用这一整个视频为我的这个说法辩护
but I think I can actually defend that statement throughout the course of this video.
而这是我的主要观点:
But this is my primary point,
虽然《死亡搁浅》宣传中是一款能让人们团结起来的游戏
the Death Stranding was advertised and held up as a game that would bring people together.
但我不禁感觉它造成的结果恰恰相反 讽刺意味颇深
And I can't help but find it extremely ironic that it is done the exact opposite.
现在 请大家坐好
Now as we move forward into the video
希望大家能听听我对这款游戏的所有评价想法
I ask that you please hear me out on all the critiques I have for the game.
另外 我也希望大家
Furthermore I'd also like for you to
能在下面的评论区贡献您的的宝贵评价
contribute all of your critiques and contributions down in the comments section below.
每条我都会看
I will be reading through all of them.
如果你想要我的简单明了的建议
Now if you'd like my concise recommendation
我觉得如果你已经被它吸引了 那玩就行了
I'd say that you should only play Death Stranding
if you have already been intrigued by it.
当然了 更可能是你已经玩过了
Which if you are, chances are you've already played it.
可惜的是 如果你对《死亡搁浅》有着任何程度的怀疑
The unfortunate reality is that if you're skeptical of Death Stranding to any degree
或者到目前为止有些地方让你感觉很厌恶这款游戏
or if there are things that have repelled you thus far,
那它很难会出现反转
the game isn't going to convince you otherwise.
而奇怪的是
And the bizarre thing is that
这似乎是小岛制作公司有意识的设计选择
it seems as though this was a conscious design choice on the part of Kojima Productions.
也可能只是他们在公然犯蠢 我们稍后会进行讨论
That or it's just blatant stupidity something that we're gonna discuss in just a moment.
而如果你有任何机会能玩到这款游戏的话
However if there is any chance that you're going to play this game
那请务必在观看视频前先玩一玩
you should do that first before watching.
放心 视频一直在这 不会长腿跑了
Don't worry, this video will still be here once you're done.
另外你还要提前知道几件事
Also a couple of things that you should know
我进行了一次参与人数超过2400的大规模调查
I did conduct a massive survey with over 2400 respondents.
顺便感谢调查的每一位参与者
Thank you, by the way, for all of you who contributed.
视频从头到尾我都会提到这个调查
And I will be mentioning it throughout the video.
调查结果我也全部放在我的个人网站上了
I have posted all of the data collected from this survey on my website lukestephens.net
方便大家随时查阅数据的真实性
so that you can sift through and hold me accountable.
如果你想参加我下一款游戏测评前的调查
If you want to participate in the next survey for the next critique,
请务必在Instagram、Twitter和Discord上关注我
make sure to follow me on Instagram, Twitter and Discord
这样你就能在我发布调查时收到通知
so that you can be notified of when I publish it.
视频中还有一些内容是关于我在游戏里收集的数据与分析
I also have a section in this video where I go over some descriptive analytics
that I performed on data that I collected while playing.
这里的内容有些很复杂 我理解大家
This is dense and kind of complicated stuff, I get that,
所以请放心 我会尽量给大家讲清楚
so rest assured that I'm going to try and make it as accessible as possible.
最后 感谢所有Patreon上的赞助者赞助了本期视频的制作
And lastly I want to thank all of these Patreons for funding the creation of this video.
说白了 没有你们就没有这期视频
Straight up, it wouldn't have been made
if these people didn't step up and contribute over on Patreon.
感谢你们所有人
Thank you to all of you.
特别鸣谢Zachary Johnson、Mike Holland
And a special vocal shout-out to Zachary Johnson, Mike Holland,
Christopher Scott和Paige Richardson的大力慷慨援助
Christopher Scott and Paige Richardson for their extreme generosity.
本期视频很长
Understand that this is a long video
所以视频下方有时间戳 方便大家跳转到自己觉得最有意思的部分
so I have timestamps below so you can jump around to chapters that you find most appealing.
另外我觉得也不用我多说
And of course it should go without saying
本期视频会有浓度极高的剧透
but this video is going to spoil pretty much everything.
所以请务必酌情观看
So consider this your spoiler warning.
想说的就是这些 我们开始吧
But with all of that said, let's get into it.
一款游戏给玩家带来的第一印象极其重要
The first impressions that a game gives the player are extremely important.
原因有很多
They're important for a variety of reasons
其中最主要的是可以说服那些对游戏质量持怀疑态度的玩家
but chief among them is that they serve to convince players who are skeptical of the game's quality
让他们能玩得下去
that they should continue playing.
可是对于一款售价60美元的游戏来说
Now normally for a $60 release,
如果有玩家心甘情愿掏那么多钱喜+1了
if somebody has gone through the trouble of paying that amount of money for the game
那么他很可能相当自信认为自己会喜欢这款游戏
chances are they're already fairly confident that they're going to enjoy the game.
既然如此 一款游戏有一个打磨精细的开篇又有什么意义呢
So what's the point of having an extremely polished first two hours or so
反正玩家已经付钱了
if players are already forking over cash.
首先我觉得制作这款游戏的艺术家们
Well, for one I would hope that the artists creating the game
希望玩家能对他们起的标题感兴趣
would want players to be intrigued by the title that they've put forward.
更进一步讲 《死亡搁浅》是一款非常两极分化的游戏
But furthermore, Death Stranding is such a polarizing game,
在游戏发售之前 它的玩法就引起了很多争论
and the gameplay was such a matter of debate before its release
许多玩家只能观看游戏预告片来决定他们是否要去尝试这款游戏
that many people watched streams and clips of the introductory hours of gameplay
to decide whether or not they were going to try it.
我去 这也太漂亮了
This is … pretty freakin gorgeous.
真的 你们看看诺曼·李杜斯这张脸
I mean for real, look at this, Norman Reedus,
从来没见过游戏里实时渲染的脸上的毛发都能这么好看
the real-time rendering of pubes on a man's face has never looked so good.
而对于小岛制作公司来说 不幸的现实是
And the unfortunate reality for Kojima Productions is that
许多人刚一上手这游戏 没玩多久就想弃了
many people started playing the game and decided to quit within the first few hours.
这是我前面提到的调查中的一些回复内容
This is a selection of responses from the survey I mentioned earlier.
在开始游戏后决定放弃的玩家中 大家的主要原因有下:
Of players who quit playing the game after starting it,
among the chief reasons why people stopped playing
认为前几小时无趣 节奏慢 无聊 令人困惑 甚至觉得与宣传中不一样
were that they said the first few hours were uninteresting, slow, boring, confusing,
and even not as advertised.
每款游戏都会有一些玩家刚开玩就放弃 这很正常
Now it's fair that every game is going to have some players who drop off after starting it.
哪怕神作也完全没法避免
That's completely unavoidable, even for a masterpiece.
但关键是 玩家进入游戏后 第一反应脑子里想的都是
But the key takeaway is that going into the game,
the major contention on everybody's minds
这游戏是否有趣 节奏快慢 是否令人困惑
were whether or not this game was going to be uninteresting, slow, boring, or confusing.
而这款游戏的前几小时肯定对这些先入为主的观念没有帮助
And the first few hours of the game certainly didn't help these preconceived notions.
那小岛具体做了什么?
But what specifically did Kojima do?
他以一种非常战略性的方式开始了这个故事
Well, he started the story in a very strategic way,
山姆只是执行普通的送货任务的无数快递员之一
where Sam is just another porter performing normal deliveries like everybody else.
游戏暗示有一支这样的快递员大军在美国本土到处送货
And it's implied that there's essentially an army of these types of porters
that are delivering packages across the continental United States.
说实话 比起其他的开场 我更喜欢这样
Now I'll be honest, I like this more than the alternative.
就像在老式的《战神》游戏中 比如《战神III》里
Like in the old school God of War games, like God of War III
本来自己一身超能力 结果被剥夺了
where you have all of the abilities up front and then they're ripped from you
然后随着游戏进行你一步步去把那些神挨个杀掉
after you've tasted the forbidden fruit
of what the player could look forward to having later in the game.
但这并不能改变这款游戏开始时非常缓慢的事实
But it doesn't change the fact that this starts very slow.
开场山姆的摩托车就没了
In the opening cutscene, Sam loses his bike.
导致游戏前几小时你只能徒步送货
And you're forced to transport cargo on foot for the first few hours.
这种情况持续了一阵
Furthermore it goes on for a while.
所以前两小时玩着真的很累
The first two hours really do feel like a trudge.
我觉得即使是游戏的粉丝也不会否认这样的评价
And I don't think that this is a controversial thing to say
even if you are a fan of the game.
我重申 我很喜欢玩《死亡搁浅》 但我说的也都是事实
Again, I enjoyed my time with Death Stranding, but this is simply a reality.
游戏最初几小时 节奏很混乱
The first few hours, the pacing is all over the place.
游戏也没有在这里介绍太多有意思的机制
There also aren't very many interesting gameplay mechanics introduced here.
指派你的任务只是给一个快死的总统送一小包药物
In fact the only missions that you're sent on
are to deliver a small package of drugs to a dying president,
协助尸体处理部的小组 看几段过场动画
assist a corpse disposal crew, you watch some cutscenes,
然后让你送已故总统的遗体去焚化场
and then you are asked to incinerate the president's body after she's croaked.
我其实对这些任务没什么意见
And I don't really have an issue with these types of deliveries.
实际上 如我之前所说 我觉得这些任务很惬意 很舒心
In fact I actually find them fairly relaxing and satisfying as I mentioned earlier.
但的确加深了人们心中《死亡搁浅》只是一个步行模拟器的刻板印象
But it does reaffirm the stereotype that Death Stranding is just a walking simulator,
尤其是这一路没什么动态的互动内容
especially because there's no real dynamic encounters,
整段旅途中连一个动物都没有
there's no animals that you'll encounter in the world when you're going on these trips.
只有背着某些货物的你自己
It's just you, walking with some type of cargo strapped to your back,
在一片开阔的空间里步履蹒跚地前行
trying to keep balance as you walk across a large open field,
唯有散落的碎石让你从A到B点的旅途中多了一点坎坷
scattered with rocks, that are just there to make it slightly tedious
for you to walk from point A to point B.
还是那句话 没说这不好
Again, not inherently bad,
只是让玩家会先入为主地认为《死亡搁浅》游戏内容只有这样的走路
it just reaffirms the preconceived notion that
Death Stranding only has walking to offer in terms of gameplay.
即使我们会发现游戏内的元素远不止此
Even though as we'll find out later in the game, there's much more to it.
游戏基本游玩内容就是从一个地方运货到另一个地方
Now the baseline gameplay loop
is made up of course of transporting cargo from one location to another
或者在哪捡到了货物后归还 说白了就是送快递的游戏
or going to one location receiving cargo and returning it, in other words, a fetch quest.
有些玩家对游戏的核心玩法提出了严厉批评
Now some people have heavily criticized the game for the core gameplay loop,
认为游戏玩法都是这种非常简单的任务 实际上我不同意这种说法
being made up of this very simple task, which I actually disagree with.
任何活动都可以变成一个游戏
Any activity can be turned into a game.
只要有足够的注意力和时间 无论是耕种 狩猎 甚至是单纯的对话
Given enough attention and time whether it's farming, hunting, or even talking,
所有这些互动都可以做成值得一玩的内容
all of these things can be turned into an experience that's worth playing.
此外 《死亡搁浅》的游戏系统在游玩过程中会变得越来越复杂
Furthermore, Death Stranding's gameplay system grows more complex over the course of the game.
有枪 有榴弹发射器 有动态的怪物BOSS战 有BT区
They had guns, grenade launchers, monster boss fights that are dynamic, BT zones,
甚至还有米尔人这种专门追踪 抓捕快递员的人类敌人
and even humanoid enemies known as MULEs
that track your every movement and can hunt you down.
但你需要游玩超过10小时左右才能看到这些东西的完整状态
However, you will need to get past around the 10-hour-mark
to see most of these things in full capacity.
甚至像榴弹发射器这种武器需要玩25到30小时才能接触到
And some of these things such as grenade launchers
aren't even introduced until 25 to 30 hours in.
这是玩这款游戏必须经历的痛苦
And this is one of the necessary frustrations with Death Stranding,
也是游戏制作组导致的
and it's a result of the studio that made it.
很多日系游戏都需要玩家花很多时间去了解世界观与游戏玩法
Like many Japanese titles your time is required to buy into the world and the gameplay.
我甚至能举出几个例子
And I actually have a few examples.
比如《怪物猎人 世界》就是我超爱玩的一款日式ARPG游戏
Monster Hunter: World for instance is a Japanese action RPG that I love to death.
它的学习路线非常陡峭 需要玩家投入很多努力
And it requires a steep learning curve and a lot of effort on the player's part
才能了解怎样组合各种不同配装才能达到最优化的数值
if you want to learn what all of the different components are
that contribute to a fully min/max build.
我已经玩了《怪物猎人 世界》大约100个小时
I've put in roughly a hundred hours into Monster Hunter: World
但每次玩还是能学到新的东西
and I'm still learning new things that the game has to offer.
另一个例子是《女神异闻录5》的序章部分
Or look at Persona 5's introductory section
根据玩家游玩风格与节奏 可以持续15-22小时
that can last by itself 15 to 22 hours depending on your play style and pace.
没错 这只是序章部分
And yes, that's considered the introduction.
重点是 日式游戏的开发与西方那些游戏很不一样
The point is, Japanese game development is different than westernized game development.
他们的游戏往往有很多内容
Their games tend to have a lot of meat to them
需要玩家花费很长时间来消化 吸收游戏里的这些内容
and they require a lot of time on the player's part
in order to buy into and understand everything that there is to offer.
而这实际上也导致很多西方玩家对这些类型的游戏感到厌恶
And this actually causes a lot of Western players to be turned off by these types of games.
有一说一 西方玩家真的很没耐性
Like it or not, western gamers are very impatient.
如果一款游戏没有在前两小时内抓住玩家眼球
And if a game is not grabbing a player within the first hour or even maybe two hours,
那他们就会弃掉
they're just gonna walk away.
这点我觉得倒是无可非议 只是我们的文化罢了
And I don't think there's anything wrong with that,
it's just a feature of our culture I suppose.
而小岛秀夫甚至知晓这点
But the point is Kojima even knew this,
因此他曾锐评美国人不具备充分欣赏
which is why he roasted Americans for not having the quote-unquote "artistic sensibilities"
《死亡搁浅》等游戏所需的“艺术细胞”
on the level required to appreciate games such as Death Stranding to their fully extent.
说实话 我自己长在美国科罗拉多州
And here's confession time, I live in the United States, in Colorado.
是个纯粹的西方玩家
I'm a western gamer through and through,
我习惯了游戏中最有趣的部分放在前面
and I am used to most of the coolest stuff in a game being front loaded
保证我的注意力能时刻被游戏展示的内容吸引
to make sure that my attention is captured, to show me what they have to offer.
比如游戏《星球大战 绝地：陨落的武士团》
Look at Star Wars Jedi: Fallen Order,
游戏前两小时内容打磨得非常非常棒
the first two hours are polished to high heaven and they are great.
抑或是《巫师3：狂猎》 前期狮鹫兽的战斗 加上……
Or The Witcher 3, where the Griffin fight is front-loaded as with some …
马赛克
这样的内容 一下就把我吸引住了
butts … which naturally sold me on it.
再比如《侠盗猎车手V》 开场就是抢劫
Or Grand Theft Auto V where the robbery sequence is front loaded
让玩家期待自己之后能“大干一票”
to show you what you can look forward to later in the game.
我要说的是 大多数西方的3A游戏
The point is, a majority of AAA western titles,
特别是那些广受好评的游戏
specifically the ones that are critically acclaimed,
游戏早期都有那些很有趣的内容
often feature front loaded gameplay sequences.
不论喜欢与否 这点在西方游戏中算是个业内基本操作
Like it or not it's sort of a standard of Western titles at this point.
而奇怪的是 《死亡搁浅》只能说是“一半”符合这一点
And the strange thing is that Death Stranding kind of meets this halfway.
我觉得它的游戏系统并没那么复杂 也没多么深奥
What I mean is that the gameplay system is not very robust,
or extremely dense and complicated,
不需要花上好几个小时的研究才能学会
requiring hours upon hours of intensive research and studying to understand it.
相反 它的游戏系统非常简单
Rather it's pretty simple,
玩家只要无脑把东西从A点送到B点就好了
and just requires the player to mindlessly deliver packages from point A to point B.
而游戏需要玩家大量投入精力的是它的叙事
What does require a huge amount of investment on the part of the player is the narrative.
就当前来说 开头部分最牛逼的场景
For instance, the best moment in this introductory section
是我们亲身经历的虚空噬灭
is the Voidout that we get to witness up-close.
很诡异 很神奇
It's bizarre and fantastic.
真的 这里有意思的东西太多了
Really, there are a lot of interesting things here
我们几分钟后会详细说
and we're gonna go over them in detail in just a few minutes.
我不知道大家怎样想 但当我第一次看到这个时
Now I don't know about you but when I saw this first
我还担心制作者不会给他们所展示的大多数内容做出解释
I was concerned that they weren't actually going to have answers
for most of the things that they were showing.
但他们真做到了
But they actually do,
而且感觉小岛秀夫想得很全面
and it looks like Kojima thought most of this through
至少思考方式真的很符合玩家心中那个小岛秀夫
at least in as bizarre way as you would expect from Kojima.
玩家只要等个大约38小时就能得到解答
You just have to wait roughly 38 hours to get those answers.
其他问题也是因此产生的：
Other problems also arise due to the fact
游戏是用日语进行叙述和编写的
that the game was developed narratively and written in Japanese
"ported" 这里是“翻译”的意思
和山姆的派送员（porter）职责双关
然后被“移植”……懂了吗？移植到了英语
and then it was "ported" … get it? … over to English.
认识到这点实际上非常重要
This is actually incredibly important to understand
我觉得这是《死亡搁浅》中很多剧情被批评的原因之一
and I think it's a reason why a lot of the writing in Death Stranding has been panned.
游戏是用日语写的
This is a Japanese written story.
所以对话是小岛和他的团队从原作翻译成英语给演员演出的
Thus the dialogue is translated from the original writings of Kojima and his team
into English for the actors.
而这有时会导致一些非常奇怪笨拙的对话
And this can at times lead to some really strange and clunky phrasings.
不着急 我们一会还会说这个问题
But don't worry we'll get to this more later.
可以说 《死亡搁浅》把一堆花里胡哨的电影镜头放在游戏开头
Now you could argue that Death Stranding front-load some of its more flashy cinematic sequences
我觉得这样评价是合理的
and I think that that's fair to say
尤其我们刚刚看到的虚空噬灭的画面
especially with that Voidout sequence that we just looked at.
但我个人认为 把更有趣的游玩内容放在开头或许更好一点
But in my opinion front-loading gameplay would have been a better idea
否则玩家会先入为主地认为游戏节奏很慢 觉得游戏无趣
due to gamers' preconceived notions that the game is slow and has uninteresting gameplay.
我也不好说 只是我的个人观点 欢迎大家在下面讨论
I don't know, that's just my opinion though, let me know your thoughts below.
此外 即使有精心制作 华丽震撼 甚至在视觉上引人入胜的剧情动画
Beyond this, even with elaborate cutscenes shown off that are very flashy interesting
and even visually intriguing shall we say,
《死亡搁浅》的前两个小时仍然非常枯燥 甚至令人困惑
these first 2 hours of Death Stranding are very bland, And even downright confusing,
我倒是还算接受 毕竟这只是个序章
which i think is actually okay because it is a prologue after all.
而且我认为 如果序章不带点迷惑和吸引力
And I think if a prologue wasn't at least somewhat confusing and intriguing
就不是一个好序章
it probably wouldn't be doing its job.
而从这里开始 故事要发展了
But from here the story progresses.
这些过场介绍了主要角色
Mostly through cutscenes featuring the main cast,
比如山姆 亚美莉 玛玛 亡人 硬汉 心人 希格斯 克利福德等
people like Sam, Fragile, Amelie, Mama, Deadman, Die-Hardman
Heartman, Higgs, Cliff and some others.
其中一些场景演出非常棒
Some of these scenes are actually really well acted.
我觉得麦斯·米科尔森拿下TGA 2019最佳表演奖是有原因的
I mean there's a reason that Mads Mikkelsen won the game award for best performance.
但其他一些场景就不那么……
But some other scenes are … well … not.
比如 蕾雅·赛杜的场景都很棒 除了台词内容一般
For instance, Léa Seydoux's scenes are universally awesome in spite of the writing.
倒不是说听懂她说啥很重要
Not because of I think that's important to understand.
我芙拉吉尔……并不是表面那般脆弱。
而是她的演出完全可以和麦斯·米科尔森分庭抗礼 这是很高的评价
In fact, her scenes are even up there with Mads Mikkelsen's, which I think is high praise.
她的对话非常干练而又充满情感
She has a very dry and yet emotional way of delivering her dialogue.
当然偶尔可能显得有点呆
And while it does seem stilted at times,
但我觉得这主要是台词的问题
I think that's mostly a result of the dialogue she's being fed.
毫无疑问 这些演员多数都足够有实力出演这部作品
There's no question that most of these actors are highly qualified to be in this piece
无论是麦斯·米科尔森 蕾雅·赛杜还是诺曼·李杜斯
whether you're looking at Mads, Léa or Norman,
他们都是天赋异禀的实力派演员
all of these guys are qualified and are very talented performers.
所以可能是我有点不讲理了
So perhaps I'm being unreasonable,
但我认为应该把大部分呆板的台词和表演归咎于导演和编剧
but to me it seems fair to blame most of the stilted lines and delivery on the direction and the writing
而不是演员
as opposed to the performances.
然而我发现有一些表演完全是诡异到令人发笑
However some of the performances that we see are downright bizarre and laughably bad.
我个人认为 游戏里演的最烂的是布丽吉特/亚美莉
In my opinion, one of the worst performances we see in the game is that of Bridget / Amelie.
场景很离谱 背景很怪异
These scenes are bizarre, they're staged strangely,
写得还又臭又长
they're written in extremely verbose ways.
而且它们的表现方式应该让人觉得是非常深刻的
And they're presented in a manner that makes it seem like it should be very profound,
结果观众眼里却像看喜剧片一样
yet it appears to the viewer almost comedic.
事实上 游戏结尾部分亚美莉叨叨了能有四十分钟
In fact at the end of the game Amelie rambles for roughly 40 minutes,
玩家还只能一边听着 啥都干不了
slathering the player in unprompted exposition.
我第一次玩到这段的时候我在卧室里
And when I was playing this for the first time I was actually in my bedroom,
我未婚妻Nikki就在床上看我玩
and my fiancee Nikki was sitting on the bed watching me play.
她当时看亚美莉终于完成她10分钟的一段独白后反应如下：
And, well, this was her reaction to Amelie
finally finishing one of her 10 minute monologue diatribes.
她都磨叽十分钟啦！
10 minutes to go!!
而在《死亡搁浅》中 很多地方都有这个毛病：
And a lot of things actually follow this trend in Death Stranding:
莫名其妙的乱节奏 对话和导演奇怪又搞笑的选择
inexplicably bad pacing, dialogue and hilariously weird directorial choices.
有些人可能会辩解说这是小岛的风格
Now some people will say that this is just Kojima's style.
他们这样说是为了给游戏古怪的设计辩护
They say this to defend the game's more eccentric design choices,
而这对我来说简直太怪了
and this is one of the weirder things to me.
这些人完全是在为没有任何意义的东西辩护
People are defending something that doesn't hold any weight themselves.
我指的“游戏中的奇怪设定”是说
What I mean is that of all of the things to conceive as weird design choices,
比如游戏角色拉屎的时候给你插播一条广告
it would be something like a planted ad while a character in the game goes poop.
这种设定大家都会觉得是“奇怪”的
That seems like something we could all agree is a weird thing to include.
但这时候一些小岛的狂热粉丝就会跳出来说“这是小岛的风格”
But the hardcore Kojima fans will defend this as part of his style,
说些“不喜欢就是没理解”这些难懂的话
and if you don't like it you simply don't get it.
我真不想在这再解释这些了
Now I don't need to explain that ad nauseam,
这明显就是一种诉诸权威谬误
the fact that this is an appeal to authority fallacy.
完全无法理解 愚蠢至极
It's completely incomprehensible and in fact it's the height of stupidity.
不过我相信如果你已经看到这了
Chances are if you've made it this far into this video,
那你肯定不是那种张口闭口就是“不喜欢就是没理解”这些话的玩家
you're not the type of person that's going to be defending a choice like this
with the defense that if you don't like it you just don't get it.
我还是要强调一下
I can't reiterate this enough.
一个东西好坏跟是不是作者风格没关系
Just because it's his style doesn't mean that something is good.
比如我现在就可以搞个独特的风格 比如录所有的东西都不做剪辑
For instance I can have a style that's very unique like filming everything without cuts
或者所有画面都加个贼辣眼睛的滤镜
or having an extreme color grade placed on all of my footage.
这可以叫我的风格
This may be my style,
但你并不能说这种风格在当前情况下就是最好的
but that doesn't always mean that it's the best option in a given situation.
这就是为什么多数大导演都有自己的风格 但仍能灵活多变
This is why most great directors have a style but they remain flexible.
无论是在应用他们的风格 还是在应用其风格的内容方面
Either in the application of their style or in the content to which they apply their style.
那些差点杀死你的 会使你变得更怪异
What doesn't kill you make you stranger.
Joker~
无脑给你做的各种事情上搞点噱头
To mindlessly apply some sort of gimmick on everything that you do
然后说这是我的风格
claiming that it's your style
在我看来算不上什么艺术表达
doesn't seem like an artistic expression to me.
更像是在摆烂
It seems like a crutch.
但这只是你看到的小岛周围这种饭圈行为例子之一
But this is just one example of this sort of sycophantic fanboy ism
that you see that surrounds Kojima.
简直迷惑行为
It's really bizarre.
我都不知道这帮脑残粉到底是杰夫·基思利请的一帮水军
And I don't know if it's just an army of accounts that Geoff Keighley has created
还是真实存在的大活人
or if there are actual people out there that
小岛放个屁都是香的
defend everything Kojima does as holy and infallible.
（有请我们的行业标杆——）小岛秀夫先生!
(Please welcome our industry icon,) Mr. Hideo Kojima
总之 这种行为真的很缺乏理性
But regardless it is the height of irrationality.
甚至我敢肯定大家现在去评论区还能找到这类人
Even now I'm sure if you look in the comments section of this video you're going to see people
把《死亡搁浅》里小岛秀夫弄的奇葩内容辩护为
defending things that Kojima did in this game and problems with Death Stranding,
“你不喜欢就是没看懂”云云
saying that "if you don't like it, you just don't get it".
不知道大家听没听过“斯德哥尔摩综合征”
Now if you don't know what Stockholm Syndrome is,
简言之就是某人会对自己本该讨厌的人产生敬仰爱慕之情
it's basically when somebody develops feelings of admiration or respect for someone with whom
they should have negative feelings.
所以我决定将小岛秀夫脑残粉的一些极端行为称为“小岛秀夫综合征”
So I'm going to call what we're seeing with these sick of fantic Kojima fans "Kojima Syndrome".
可能大家还能想到比这更合适的词 但……
Maybe somebody else has come up with a name for this that's more fitting but …
我就用这个词了 因为它很像斯德哥尔摩综合征
I'm calling it "Kojima Syndrome" because it's like Stockholm Syndrome
想想还挺好笑的
and I find it kind of funny.
我们来找一些临床上的病例
Let's try applying this to several examples.
游戏中几乎没有任何动物
There are little to no animals in the game.
只在游戏开场动画里看到了不少
Even though we see a plethora of them in the introductory cutscene of the title.
这究竟是技术的限制还是预算的不足?
Is this a lazy short coming due to technical restraints or budgetary restrictions?
元讨论：对讨论的讨论
抑或是对没有生命的自然的空虚和人类在更大尺度中所扮演角色的元讨论?
Or is it a meta discussion of the emptiness of nature without conscious life
and mankind's role within nature on a larger scale?
典型的小岛秀夫综合征
Who can say? Kojima Syndrome!
再比如游戏的BOSS战都很笨拙
Or the fact that all of the boss fights are extremely clunky
加上游戏主角遣返者的慷慨设定 玩家在BOSS战中并没有感觉到太大压力
and don't actually put the player in much physical danger
with the extremely generous reload system that they've put in place with the repatriation.
这是游戏设计的失败 还是开发团队的缺点？
Again, is this just bad gameplay design? A shortcoming of the development team?
还是想表达人在面对死亡时的那种无助感？
Or is it a statement on the helplessness of man in the face of death?
小岛秀夫综合征！
Kojima Syndrome!
再或者 玩家在游戏中多数的互动都是这些全息影像
Or lastly, the fact that you mostly interact with humans through holograms,
无论货送到哪都是这些复制粘贴的动作与对话
copy and pasted throughout the world whenever you deliver products back and forth.
这种复制粘贴是为了加快开发 尽早发布游戏吗？
Is this simply lazy copy and pasted content to speed up development and get a game out quickly?
还是想表达我们有多么依赖那些能拉近我们距离的科技？
Or is it a commentary on how reliant we are on technology that brings us all together?
又出现了 小岛秀夫综合征
Again, Kojima Syndrome.
你们要是不同意我说的也没事
If you're not convinced of this that's fine.
保持一个开放的态度继续往下看就知道了
Just keep an open mind moving forward through the next few sections.
后面还有很多小岛秀夫综合征发作的例子
But I do have many more examples of when Kojima Syndrome rears its ugly head.
但说了这么多 我其实想让大家知道
But having said all of that I want you to know
我对《死亡搁浅》还是有一些积极感受的
that I do have some fond feelings for Death Stranding.
我觉得我玩得很放松 甚至很治愈
I found my time relaxing even rejuvenating.
但游戏客观上也的确存在一些糟糕的元素需要指出
But there are objectively bad elements the Death Stranding has that deserve to be called out.
不能因为科乐美对小岛秀夫干的那些操蛋事就不去批评他
Kojima isn't immune to criticism, just because Konami screwed him over.
因此 尽管我多数时间很享受这款游戏
And despite largely enjoying my time of the game
但我有义务指出它的缺点 公平地评价这款游戏
I do have an obligation to call these things out and to critique the game fairly.
所以可能看起来我总在喷这个游戏 但别忘了
So while it may seem that I'm only criticizing the game remember that
首先 本期视频是一期游戏评测 其实这条理由就够了
for one this is a critique, and that's well kind of the point.
其次 我相当享受《死亡搁浅》这款游戏 后面我还会细说这部分
And two I enjoy Death Stranding writ large, and I'll be elaborating more on those parts later.
总体而言 游戏很有趣 展现了一些原创的想法
Overall the game is interesting and it lays out some original ideas.
但游戏的第一印象对此并没有太大帮助
But initial impressions don't do much to help it.
而我当然不会只浮于表面
But I don't ever settle for the surface level,
如果你看过本频道其他视频 肯定也了解这点
and if you've watched this channel you'll be well aware of that.
所以我们一起来详细看看整个游戏
So, let's go through the whole game.
我知道每个地方讲的太细可能会矫枉过正
I know this may seem like overkill and excessively detailed
但我觉得这样一款两极分化的游戏 值得我们这样去深入探讨
but if any game ever deserved such a deep dive it would be this,
the most polarizing game of this generation.
游戏包含15个主线章节
So the game consists of 15 main story driven chapters,
每个章节都包含若干个需要完成的派送订单
each of which contain a plethora of orders that you need to complete.
这些章节是：序章 派送员
They are as follows the prologue Porter,
然后第1章 布丽吉特 第2章 亚美莉
and then episodes Bridget, Amelie,
第3章 芙拉吉尔 按需要完成订单数算的话是最长的章节
Fragile, which is by far the longest chapter in terms of content and orders to be completed,
接着是昂格尔 玛玛 亡人 克利福德 心人 希格斯 硬汉
Unger, Mama, Deadman, Clifford, Heartman, Higgs, die Hardman,
克利福德·昂格尔 布里吉斯 山姆·斯特兰德 洛
Clifford Unger, Bridges, Sam Strand, Lou,
和最后一章 未来在你手中
and the last chapter Tomorrow is in your hands,
它不太算是一个章节 我们稍后会说到
which is sort of a chapter but also not, we'll talk about this more in a minute.
目前 绝大多数玩家 包括《死亡搁浅》的维基版主
Now most people including the official Death Stranding Wiki moderators
都习惯于把这些章节分成三个部分
tend to separate all of these episodes into one of three acts.
第一幕是序章到第4章
Act 1 is the prologue through Episode 4,
第二幕是第5-10章
Act 2 is Episodes 5 through 10,
第三幕是第11-14章
and Act 3 is Episodes 11 through 14
第15章是游戏主线剧情结束后的状态
with Episode 15 being the perpetual end game state of the game
还是 我们稍后再说
which again we're gonna address later.
每一幕都有它的重点
Now each act has its own focus.
第一幕重点介绍游戏系统和故事
Act 1 is focused on introducing the gameplay systems and the story,
我个人认为是三幕里面最短也是最烂的
and in my opinion this is the shortest and worst of all the three acts.
这就是玩家常说的 想玩进去这个游戏必须要过的坎
This is often what people are talking about
when they say most players have to get over the hump.
第二幕重点是游戏的玩法
Act 2 is gameplay focused,
其中为玩家带来大量游玩与视觉观感上的全新内容
and it introduces a ton of new areas both visually and in terms of gameplay.
还有升级的装备 让玩法有了更多的可能
It features upgraded equipment and really lets the line out for the player.
这一幕自由度非常高
This section is the most dynamic
玩家想接多少就接多少订单
because the player can add in as many of these standard ordered quests as they want,
还有一些动态任务 主要内容是
or they can engage with the dynamic quests which are centered around
在地图上拾取其他玩家遗弃的包裹 送到它们原有的目的地
finding other players abandoned packages and delivering them to their original destinations.
这些任务玩家可接可不接
These can be as numerous or as scarce as the player wants.
这是个很不错的方法提醒玩家这个世界还有其他人存在
It's a nice way of reminding the player that there are other people that exist in the world
即使你看不到它们 我们稍后还会讲到
even if you don't see them which is what we're going to talk about later.
而说实话 我很喜欢这个设计
But to be honest I really like this.
如果我的包裹丢了 那它不会彻底丢失
The idea that if I drop a package it's not a total loss.
会有别的玩家遇到 捡走 帮我送到目的地
And that somebody else may come along pick it up and deliver it for me.
他们也会获得“点赞” 而点赞是《死亡搁浅》中通用的社交货币
They'll get likes out of it which is the social currency that features in Death Stranding,
而我的包裹送到之后 我也会获得一些点赞
and I will also get some likes because my package has been delivered.
很简单的“我为人人 人人为我”的机制 很多游戏都有
It's the basic you scratch my back I'll scratch yours mechanic
that you see in MANY many games.
而在本作中 这个机制让玩家觉得自己与全世界其他玩家连接了起来
But in this case it's used to make the player feel as though
they're connected with players from around the world
即使你我却无法相见 无法交流 只能通过这些间接的途径互动
who they will never see,
speak to, or interact with in any way other than these indirect interactions,
比如游戏中的指示牌 或者玩家制造的发电机 高空滑索 寄存筒之类装备
through signs, pieces of equipment that you craft
such as generators zip-lines post boxes and the like.
当然 还有散落在世界各处 自行决定拾取与否的包裹
And of course also these packages that you pick up dynamically throughout the world.
这些元素的具体位置似乎是相当随机的
Now in terms of specific placement of all of these things, it seems pretty random
我统计了很多数据 稍后会列出
and I actually did a lot of math to back this up which again we'll talk about later.
我好像一直在说“稍后再说” 我保证真的会讲到
I know I'm saying that for everything but I promise we'll get to it.
第三幕以叙事为中心 把之前各种碎片拼凑起来
Act 3 is narratively focused with lots of smaller sections pieced together.
这些章节发生在很多不同的地点
As many varied chapters in all different locations
从一战到二战 再到越战 还有大雪山
that span from World War I to World War II, to Vietnam all the way to a snowy mountain site.
这些剧情算是对那些玩到这里的玩家的奖励
These really are the narrative reward for the players who have made it this far,
“这里”指游戏时间20-25小时
this far, being roughly 20 to 25 hours.
有大量非常长的过场动画
There are a ton of very long cutscenes
有5分钟的 有15分钟的 最长有40分钟的
that span anywhere from 5 minutes to 15 to 40 minutes long.
玩到这的时候一定要备好瓜子饮料矿泉水
So make sure you've got your popcorn popped before you head into the last few chapters.
我还想说 这幕有些剧情演出真的非常棒
But I do want to say there are some fantastic performances as I said earlier.
说的就是你 拔叔
I'm looking at you Mads.
伴随着主线的进行 玩家还会探索游戏的地图
Now through all these chapters you're exploring the map,
《死亡搁浅》使用的是Decima引擎
Death Stranding was of course made with the Decima Engine
之前在《地平线 零之曙光》上使用过
which is the same engine that was used for Horizon Zero Dawn
展现出了大量高度多样化的生物群落
which itself featured a plethora of highly varied biomes
让玩家感觉游戏中的世界比实际大得多
and made the world feel as though it spanned a much larger area than it actually did.
可能是我太挑了 但我感觉本作的游戏世界并没有最初展现的那样丰富多彩
And I might be picky but it seems as though this world really isn't as varied
as it was initially made out to be.
虽然地图上说是横跨整个美国本土
Even though it's meant to span effectively the entire United States,
但感觉真的没那么大
it really doesn't feel extremely large.
实际上 游戏结尾的订单
In fact at the very end of the game one of your final assignments
就是要你横跨整个美国 重走你走过的路
is to cross back over every square inch of the map that you've traveled
徒步回到东海岸
to get back to the east coast on foot.
我喜欢这个任务背后的用意
I like the meta implications of this assignment
让你重新回到起点 看看自己走了多远
because it makes you go back and see how far you've come.
但我玩的时候发现 其实只要20到30分钟就走完了
But when I was doing this I realized it only took me 20 to 30 minutes to travel all that way.
确实可能是我太挑了
And again maybe I'm being picky,
但这样的地图要是代表整个美国本土的话
but it seems as though for a map that's supposed to represent the entire United States,
那它确实不怎么大
it really isn't very big.
跑题了
But I digress.
我们将在后面的游戏玩法部分讨论这个问题
We'll discuss that more later in the gameplay section
届时我们还会讲到游戏世界的布局与构造
when we address the world's layout and construction.
但我们现在先来说说游戏的开场
But for now let's discuss the opening of the game.
正如我之前所说 《死亡搁浅》的开场效果一般
As I stated earlier, the opening of Death Stranding isn't very effective.
于是问题来了：什么才算效果好？
But this does beg the question: what would be effective?
这里我说的效果好坏 指的是游戏开场
Now by effective, I mean what do the opening hours have to achieve
能否说服那些持怀疑态度的玩家
and in order to convince players skeptical and not
让他们看过开场后觉得这游戏值得继续玩下去
that it's actually worth playing past these opening hours.
在我看来 每个游戏开场效果的好坏要看具体情况
Now in my estimation it seems that for each game
在我看来 每个游戏开场的效果好坏要看具体情况
this is going to be different depending on the context.
比如《辐射4》或《赛博朋克2077》开场带来的效果是不同的
What I mean is that the opening hours of Fallout 4 or Cyberpunk 2077 are going to be different
因为两者宣发力度不同
depending on how they were pitched,
公众对制作发行游戏的公司的最初看法也不同
the public's perception of the company that's publishing and creating the game.
甚至还会受到诸如游戏标价这类东西的影响
And it can even be influenced by something as generic as the price tag.
比如一个标价60美元的游戏 人们肯定想看到一款精心打磨后的3A大作
For a $60 game for instance, one would expect an extremely expansive polished experience.
而如果小岛秀夫让《死亡搁浅》只定价40美元
Whereas if Kojima were to only charge $40 for Death Stranding,
人们就不会带着那么大的期待开始玩了
people would go into it with a lesser expectation.
这也是为什么顽皮狗发布《神秘海域：失落的遗产》
This is why Naughty Dog when they released The Lost Legacy
这款可能很多玩家没听过的 独立的《神秘海域》作品时
which was actually a standalone Uncharted game even though most people haven't heard of it,
玩家能够接受它只有六个小时左右的流程
they were able to get away with an experience that's only 6 hours long
这个流程相比《神秘海域4》已经相当短了
and is very very narrow compared to that of Uncharted 4,
一切都是因为这游戏只卖40美元
all because they only charged $40 for the game out of the gate.
玩家心里有数 而游戏也达到了玩家的期望
They set the expectation and then the game was able to live up to that expectation.
对于《死亡搁浅》 玩家有很多先入为主的观念带入了游戏中
With Death Stranding, there are a lot of preconceived notions
that players have and had going into it.
在我看来 《死亡搁浅》应该尽力说服大量持怀疑态度的人
To me it seems as though Death Stranding should have tried to convince a lot of skeptical people
告诉他们玩家并不是批评者口中的那样
that the game isn't that which its critics claim it to be.
当然了 小岛粉丝们无论如何都会感兴趣
Of course fans of Kojima's work were going to be interested regardless.
他们肯定要把游戏打通关的
They were going to play it all the way through no matter what.
这也反映在我对《死亡搁浅》的玩家所做的调查中
And this is reflected in the pole that I took of players of Death Stranding.
但游戏必须说服新玩家它自身的游玩价值
But new players have to be convinced of its worth.
我觉得这是个无可争议的点
And I don't even think this is a controversial thing to say
但我总感觉评论区会有些反对意见
but I'm sure there will be some disagreeing in the comments.
但请听我细细道来
But at least hear me out.
我的意思具体而言 《死亡搁浅》必须证明：
Specifically what I mean is that Death Stranding has to prove that
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
其一 游戏拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
for one, it has a rewarding and worthwhile gameplay loop;
其二 游戏的叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
and for two, the narrative makes sense and has been thought through.
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
尤其第一点 因为这款游戏在发布前被许多人称为步行模拟器
Specifically number one because this was referred to as a walking simulator
by many before launch,
我并不同意这点 稍后我会讲到
which I actually disagree with, but again I'll discuss that later.
我知道我说好多次了 但我保证会
I know I've said that a thousand times but I will.
关键是对于像我这样的新玩家来说
The point is for new players coming in such as myself
除了《PT》等小项目外 我几乎没怎么玩过小岛的游戏
having had no major experience to Kojima other than with PT and smaller projects,
所以大家从最开始就会受到“步行模拟器”这种说法影响
they are going to have this in mind from the very beginning.
大家会带着先入为主的想法来玩《死亡搁浅》
They're going to be approaching Death Stranding with the preconceived idea
觉得它就是个步行模拟器 游玩内容很糟糕 很无聊
that it is a walking simulator with gameplay that's unsatisfying and boring.
小岛需要做的 就是在《死亡搁浅》的开场几个小时里
All Kojima would have to do is create the opening hours of Death Stranding in such a way
让玩家相信这个游戏系统比玩之前想象中的更丰富
that players would be convinced that
there was more to this gameplay system than initially seemed present.
小岛有很多方法做到这一点
Kojima could have done this in a plethora of ways.
首先 他可以用一场大规模的BT战来开始游戏
For one he could have started the game with a massive BT battle,
不要播片 上来就开干
not just a cutscene of it, but an actual gameplay system
让玩家知道你可以像后面一样 和这些怪物战斗
showing how you can fight these things as you do later on.
或者他还可以在前几个小时播片展示这些BT
Or he could have kept the large cutscene that shows off these BTs in the first couple of hours
但在其中增添一些互动内容
and just added some interactive parts to it,
比如加入一些QTE 就像顽皮狗在他们各种游戏中做的那样
Quick Time Events in effect, same thing that Naughty Dog does with all of their games.
再次强调 所有人都认同小岛在《死亡搁浅》中创造的美丽而玄幻的世界
Again nobody was skeptical of the fact
that Kojima had a really beautiful and bizarre world to play with in Death Stranding.
大家怀疑的是支撑起这个故事的游戏性
What they doubted was the gameplay that backed that story up.
可能有人认为开场这些东西其实无伤大雅
Now some of you may think that all of these things shouldn't be very important.
可正是开场决定了玩家是会继续玩上个50小时
But this is what is either going to hook players into a 50 hour playthrough
还是玩了一小时后就弃了吃灰
or rappel players after a single hour of playing.
可能又有人会在评论区拿出些陈词滥调说
And before the pedantic comment comes along where somebody says
一小时不足以判定游戏的好坏 这些话
that an hour isn't enough time to determine if the game is good or not,
我真诚地表示反对 我觉得足够了
I respectfully disagree, it should be enough.
毕竟一小时也不短了
An hour is a long time after all.
虽然一个节奏差的游戏 很可能是开头一小时很烂
Though often the pacing of a game can be so awful that the first hour is terrible
然后后半部分做的非常好
yet the later sections are great.
但我要承认这得分人
But I will admit that this is a personal preference.
有些玩家喜欢在游戏中投入几十个小时的耐心
Some people are willing to grind through dozens upon dozens of hours of content
最终品尝到游戏的精髓所在
before they get to the meat of the game,
而我个人并不能接受这点
while I personally think that that's unacceptable.
但无论如何 我觉得这并不难吧？
Regardless this all should be easy enough to do, right?
小岛秀夫应该有能力创造一个吸引玩家眼球的开场内容
Kojima should be able to create an opening sequence that pulls people in.
他只需要向玩家展示一些精彩的游戏玩法
He just would have had to show players some flashy gameplay,
并用引人入胜的叙事内容吸引他们
and hook them with an intriguing narrative mechanism.
但是没有 小岛在这方面完全失败了 我想我可以说服大家
But no, Kojima completely fails at this, and I think I can convince you.
我会带大家过一遍游戏开场内容
To do this, I want to go through the opening sequence of the game.
并且我会把《死亡搁浅》要证明的这两件事放在屏幕上方
And I'm actually going to keep these two things that Death Stranding has to prove up on screen.
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
这样 当我们浏览画面时
That way as we go through this
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
可以不断问自己 这两条有没有满足
you can consistently ask yourself whether or not these checks are being met.
因为不管喜欢与否 这都是玩家在经历开场时心里有意无意都在问的问题
Because like it or not this is the mental check that players are going to be applying
as they go through the opening sequence consciously or not.
《死亡搁浅》以安部公房的诗《绳》作为开场……
Death Stranding opens with what is presented as a profound quote from Kobo Abe's poem "Nawa" …
“绳索”与“棍棒”是人类最早发明的两种工具。
绳索可以将好东西收归在身边，棍棒则可以抵挡麻烦。
两者皆是我们最早的朋友，皆由我们创造。
有人的地方，就有绳索与棍棒。
——摘自安部公房的《绳》
我不知道有没有念对他的名字
I don't know if I'm pronouncing that name right …
安倍？安部？ 爱谁谁吧
I'm gonna be perfect Kobo Abe's … Kobo Abe … I have no idea.
总之 这首诗在当时并没有什么关联
Regardless it's not that relevant at the moment.
而当最后联系上游戏叙事内容的时候
And even when it is explained and tied back into the narrative,
诗句的解释也十分贫乏
it fails to feel completely and truly profound,
尤其是亡人在游戏结尾部分最后引用它的时候
specifically when Deadman quotes it at the very end of the game.
总统一定知道会发生这样的事。
很讽刺，不是吗？
引发危机的这把枪，最后成为了拯救你的关键。
亚美莉……她说过这把枪有别的用处。
它不是武器，是救生索，就像棍棒变成了绳子。
我想可以这么说吧……
诗句引用后继续播片
After the excerpt is shown and plays off,
大量绝美的景色 中间带着制作组的名单
the credits rolling with a ton of beautiful landscape shots,
我不知道大家怎么想
and I don't know about you
但最初我以为这些都是引擎中或游戏中实机的截图或片段
but initially I thought these were all in engine or in-game screenshots or clips
展示我们在游戏中将要探索的土地
to show us the lands that we were going to be exploring as we went through the game,
我当时真的很兴奋
and I got really excited.
但后来经过进一步调查
However upon further investigation it actually turns out
我从论坛上一些人口中得知
according to most people on the forums I've read through
这些画面其实是参考照片
the consensus seems to be that these are actually the reference photos
是小岛制作全公司去冰岛旅游
that Kojima Productions took when they did a company trip to Iceland
拍摄的给游戏中风景作为参考的照片
to get reference photos for the landscapes within the game.
他们后来在参考图中加入了游戏中的一些元素 比如开罗尔物质等
They put in some references to the later games such as the Chiralium hands and things,
但……总之仅此而已 这些只是风景图罢了
but … there really isn't much here, it's just photos of landscapes.
但确实很漂亮 向大家展示了游戏想要模仿的画面
Regardless, it's pretty and it shows you what they were trying to mimic,
而事实上游戏引擎能够做出类似的画面
and the fact that it looks as though it could be in engine says everything.
让游戏引擎展现出如此魅力的画面是非常令人印象深刻的
It's really impressive that the engine is able to push things that could look this good.
即使游玩过程中效果可能达不到照片那么高的标准
Even if in effect and in practice when you're playing through the game,
they don't hold up to this standard.
这些画面过后 游戏以山姆骑摩托车穿过葱郁又嶙峋的山边开始
After these shots, the game opens up with Sam Porter riding a motorcycle
across a lush green rocky mountain side.
绚丽的画面直接就把玩家带进了电影化的体验中
It's really pretty, and it shows just what kind of cinematic experience you're in for.
天下起了雨 稍后你会了解到这个叫“时间雨”
It's raining, and this rain you'll come to find out is known as "timefall",
触碰到这种雨的物体时间流速会大大加快
which makes everything it touches age at an extremely fast rate.
这个设定对游戏的剧情和玩法都有很大的影响
This has a ton of implications on game play in addition to the story
我们稍后再讲
but again we'll get to that later.
大家能够看到时间雨对他的头发 对地上的植被
As he's riding you see the timefall take effect on his hair, the grass, the plants,
当然还有对背景里穿行在山区的动物们的影响
and of course the animals that you see running across the mountainside.
虽然之后游戏中几乎再也看不到动物了
Even though you're not going to see hardly any of these things later on,
但这里展现时间雨的威力感觉还是挺酷的
it's still really cool and it shows you just what this rain can do.
山姆加速离开这里 然后突然……
Sam speeds off and then all of a sudden …
没错 你差点撞死她
Yeah, you seemingly run into her.
不过她能够传送到一个冥滩中 “冥滩”是游戏中的另一个世界
Turns out she can teleport away to a Beach which is this game world's effective purgatory.
每个人死后都会去他们自己的冥滩中
Basically when somebody dies they go to their own Beach,
这是此生与来生之间过渡的地带
and this is the intermediate place between this life and the afterlife.
这个世界中有些人能够自由穿梭于自己的冥滩
Some people in this world can actually interact freely with their Beaches
以此实现传送 甚至还能死而复生
and use it to teleport around or to even at times come back from the dead
后者这样的人成为“遣返者”
which is what is referred to in the game as "Repatriation",
山姆就是其中之一 因此他在游戏中死亡后能重新复活
Sam, being one of them which is how the game explains
how you can die in gameplay and come back to life.
刚刚的摩托车翻下悬崖报废了
Regardless the bike goes over the side of a cliff and is destroyed.
但玩过这么多游戏的大家
However if you know anything about video games,
肯定能想到自己之后还能开上一辆新的
you'll realize that you will eventually get access to one of these soon enough,
毕竟不然呢？
because why the hell not?
制作组花心思设计出那样的摩托车
The developers spent all this time making the bike,
肯定不会只用在过场动画里
surely they would not just have done that for a cutscene.
玩家此时只能开始徒步前进
Realizing that you now have to travel on foot,
你捡起了散落一地的包裹 开始向目的地进发
you collect the packages that fell off and you start walking.
最后你来到一个山洞 在里面和芙拉吉尔进行了一段对话
You eventually stumble into a cave and you talk with Fragile of it.
这里提到山姆暴露在开罗尔物质下会流泪的体质
Here it's explained that Sam cries whenever he's exposed to something called Chiralium,
芙拉吉尔也有这种过敏反应
and Fragile has the same allergic reaction.
我们还见到了第一个“冥滩上的东西” 简称BT
We also see our first "BT", or "Beached thing".
小岛特爱整这种缩写
Yeah, Kojima loves his abbreviations as you'll see.
新玩家看到这可能会一头雾水……
Now these don't make a lot of sense to new players …
草 可能玩过很久的玩家也难以接受
'hell maybe they don't even make sense to late-game players.
但大多时候 游戏开场部分根本没想给大家解释这些东西
But mostly they don't try to explain these things at all in the opening sections of the game.
游戏把这切都留给玩家想象
They leave it all up to the imagination of the player
别的不用管 只要相信这些能说得通就好了
and ask them just to take it on blind faith that this makes sense.
大家可能会觉得如果游戏介绍了一种看不见的怪物
One would think that if a story features monsters who are invisible,
看上去用手走路 靠触摸来感知生命 消遣时光
and apparently have hands as feet, and can sense life-forces and pastime with their touch,
那这背后的解释应该会很深奥 很令人震撼
that they would have some sort of massive or mind-blowing explanation
比如这些东西是如何出现的 它们是什么 它们在这个世界的作用是什么
of how these things came into existence, what they are, their role in the world,
以及这个世界中的人们如何与它们互动
and how the people that inhabit the world, interact with them.
我不是说制作组需要立即为这些问题给出答案
No I'm not saying that Kojima Productions has to explain all of these things immediately.
实际上我觉得上来就把一切告诉你的故事会非常糟糕
In fact I think that would make a pretty terrible story
if everything was exposed at all at once.
但这看起来的确让《死亡搁浅》迷失得有点远
But it does make Death Stranding appear as though
it is suffering from a severe case of "lost-itis".
就是说 他们在游戏世界中创造了太多很诡异的内容
Namely that they were doing and establishing really weird things in the world
只是因为这些东西看上去很酷炫很抢眼
just because it looked cool and was crazy and eye-catching.
实际上 制作《地平线 零之曙光》的游骑兵工作室的开发者强烈反对这种行为
This is actually something that the developers over at Guerrilla Games,
the creators of Horizon Zero Dawn, hazard against vehemently.
如果你看了他们创作	《地平线 零之曙光》的纪录片
In fact if you watch the documentary explaining how they created Horizon Zero Dawn
就应该听过他们关于“酷的规则”的探讨
you'll hear them discuss what they call "the rule of cool".
简言之 你不应该只是因为“酷” 就随便把什么东西塞进游戏里
This is basically the idea that you should never put something in the game
just because it's cool.
他说的也确实非常在理
And this is also true of the story.
如果制作组掉进了这个坑里
If you start falling victim and prey to the rule of cool,
那么游戏很容易就会变成一堆会喷火的机械恐龙互射激光
all of a sudden the game is going to be nothing but dinosaurs that shoot lasers
所有角色都是半裸之类辣眼睛的作品
and have flamethrowers and everybody is half-naked.
把持不住 很容易失控
It's gonna get out of hand really quickly.
其次 制作组还容易掉进不停圆场解释设定的坑中
Furthermore, you can get yourself into a lot of trouble
trying to write your way out of this hole.
美剧《迷失》最后就是这样
The TV show Lost ended up in this exact position.
塞了一堆花里胡哨的东西
When they had a lot of really cool crazy things they were showing off,
结果他们完全不知道之后该怎么讲通这些东西
even though they had no idea how they were going to explain it later on.
有些玩家会接受这样
Now some people will just accept this writ large.
他们会接受这些在游戏世界中是有意义的
They'll accept that it makes sense within the world,
他们会按照制作组想要的方式去体验游戏
and they'll experience the game the way that the writer wants them to.
然而现实是 很多玩家对小岛和他的编剧能力非常怀疑
However the reality is that a lot of players are extremely skeptical of Kojima
and his writing ability.
因此不管喜欢与否 这都无法说服那些
So love it or hate it this doesn't do much of anything to convince players
对小岛和他在这里建立的游戏世界持怀疑态度的玩家
who were skeptical of Kojima and the world that he's established here
让他们相信小岛已经把一切安排明白了
that he's actually thought everything through and that this makes sense.
我其实也很害怕这点
And I suffered from this fear as well.
游玩开场几小时内容时
As I play through these opening hours,
我自己总是在担忧他们没办法把眼前的一切解释清楚
the fear was real that they hadn't actually backed up any of this stuff.
说真的 人们身前罐子里的婴儿到底要怎么能解释得通？
I mean seriously, how are they possibly going to explain a bunch of babies
that are carried around in tanks on people's bellies
或是在焦油中游来游去的怪物 离远了又会突然消失
or monsters that swim in tar that somehow disappears instantly
after some arbitrary distance has been achieved.
但还好 谢天谢地 小岛秀夫的确提前经过了深思熟虑
But I'm happy to report thankfully Kojima did think all of this stuff through,
他也的确对这些内容 原理等给出了一些答案
and he does have some answers as to why these things work the way they do
虽然可能有点抽象 有点离谱
even if they are vague and kind of insane.
至于这些答案是否足够好 就是另一回事了
However as to whether or not those answers are good is another question entirely.
这也是个不错的切入点 既然聊到这就说说吧
And this is a slight tangent but we need to discuss this at some point so why not now.
对于像《死亡搁浅》这样一个奇怪的世界 玩家自然会有某种期望
With a world as strange as Death Stranding's, players rightly have a certain expectation.
即 世界观是经过深思熟虑 是说得通的
Namely that the world is thought-out and consistent.
即使这个世界没出现在科幻玄幻故事中 也不会有人说它假 说它离谱
No one cares if a world is unrealistic or crazy
that's never held back sci-fi or fantasy stories before.
相反 玩家只是希望这个世界按照它应有的设定去运转就好
Rather, we just ask that the world live according to the rules that are supposed to govern it.
比如 如果你在看《星球大战》
For instance if you were watching Star Wars,
邪恶的西斯尊主在一艘飞船上和一群外星人唠家常
and the evil Sith Lord is chilling out on a spaceship with a bunch of aliens,
同时用一种称为“原力”的神奇力量感知其他人的能量
while sensing other people's energy using a magical power called the Force,
并以光速穿越一个想象中的星系 你并不会觉得怎样！
and traveling at Lightspeed through an imaginary galaxy, you wouldn't care!
因为这些都符合这个故事世界观中的法则
Because the laws of the universe that that story takes place within allow that.
但假如西斯尊主突然用他胸前两个按钮打Bbox来暂停时间
But if the Sith Lord all of a sudden was able to freeze time itself
by bboxing and rubbing his nipples,
那你早就掀桌了……
you would immediately be turned off …
好吧……我这例子可能……总之你们懂我意思！
Well … maybe not in … in that way, but nevermind!
关键是必须保持一致
Point is you have to be consistent.
我对《死亡搁浅》中神奇的异次元鲸鱼没意见
I'm fine with Death Stranding having magical interdimensional whales,
对加速时间流逝的降雨没意见 甚至对诺曼·李杜斯也没意见
rain that causes time to pass at crazy fast rates and even Norman Reedus.
我只求这一切是经过深思熟虑的 是合理的就好
But all I ask is that it's thought out and justified.
总之 继续
Anyways moving on.
与芙拉吉尔对话完 你拾起行囊 继续向城市进发
Once you're done talking with fragile you grab up your stuff and deliver it to the city.
你来到一段美丽的山谷 音乐响起 你步入其中
You walk through a beautiful Valley as music plays and you enter it.
袅袅余音配良辰美景
This music is really peaceful the scenery is beautiful.
可是等下 你还在送快递呢
But again, you're just walking with a package on your back.
这些能满足之前提到的两点要求吗？
Does this achieve either of the two things outlined earlier?
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
我觉得不能
I don't think so.
你走进建筑群 发现城市实际上出奇地空荡
As you walk into the complex, you realize that the compound is actually remarkably bland.
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
跟死城一样 一个活人都没有
And it looks dead, there's no one here.
事实上 在整个50小时的游戏流程中
In fact pretty much everyone we're going to be talking to
所有和我们交谈的人几乎都是全息影像
in any of these places throughout the entire 50 hour campaign,
they're all gonna be Holograms.
我们甚至根本见不到他们本人 这肯定是有原因的吧……
We're not even going to meet them in person for reasons.
来了来了 小岛秀夫综合征
Again, Kojima Syndrome.
你帮助尸体处理部的员工运送一具尸体出城火化
You assisted body disposal crew and take a dead body out of the city to have it incinerated.
你还不清楚发生什么大事了 但他们看起来表情非常非常严肃
You don't know exactly what the big deal is but they seem to be taking it very very seriously.
于是你继续玩下去
So, you play along.
这里玩家参与的互动不多 你只是在控制相机视角
There really isn't any player control here you at one point can control the camera
静静观看这段过场动画
while you're watching a cutscene play out.
我想他们可能是想避免连续播40分钟的动画？
I guess this was their way of avoiding a 40-minute cutscene again?
可它说到底还是在播片……算了 对我来说不重要
But it is still a cutscene so … it doesn't really do it for me.
你们驱车驶离城市 然后车辆遇袭撞毁
You drive out of the city and eventually your car is assaulted and crashes.
剧情随后向大家介绍了希格斯
Here along cutscene plays that introduces us to Higgs
他的名字来自于希格斯玻色子 我太喜欢这个充满书呆子气的名字了
who's named after the Higgs boson, a nerdy reference that I appreciated way too much.
这个场景也提出了相当多的问题
And this cutscene raises a lot of questions,
至少对于电子游戏来说 我觉得这段效果非常不错
but I think it achieved something very good, at least for a video game.
玩家很奇怪希格斯这人是谁 在做什么
It's intriguing who is this guy, Higgs, what is he doing,
他为什么能飞 他怎么召唤这些怪物的
why can he fly, how is he summoning these monsters,
为什么雨会让这个人瞬间变老
why does the rain make this guy turn old instantly,
为什么这个人被悬空吊起之后就开始拿刀捅自己想要自杀
why did the guy start stabbing himself trying to kill himself
the second that he started getting lift in the air,
他为什么会被悬空吊起
why is he being lifted in the air,
为什么尸体开始分解腐烂的时候会突然疯狂颤抖
why is it that when bodies begin to decompose they start shaking violently,
这到底是怎么回事
what the hell is this.
这些都是很合理的问题
All of these are fair questions
我觉得它们能驱动玩家想要继续玩下去追寻答案
and I think they motivate the player to want to play more to have these questions answered.
同样 我认为游戏序章的作用往往是
Again the role of a prologue I think often
给玩家读者等正在经历这些的人抛出一大堆问题
is to pose a lot of these questions to the reader player or whoever is experiencing them.
这些问题我觉得不需要一一解答
I don't think they have to all be answered
我甚至不希望它们在开场的时候就有答案
and I wouldn't even want them to all be answered in the opening sequence.
然而 在《死亡搁浅》这样特定的环境下
However with Death Stranding's specific circumstance,
这一切还是不禁让人想入为主地认为
this doesn't do much to shake the preconceived notion again,
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
这一切只是为了酷炫而加进去的离谱场景
that this is all just crazy and done for the sake of being cool.
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
总之 发生了一大堆奇怪的事件
Anyway, a bunch of weird stuff happens.
结果就是出现一个巨大的坑 中央还有一个巨大的黑手印
This results in a massive crater and a handprint indentation in the land.
这实际上就是在整个游戏中用致命武器杀人有多糟心的原因
This is actually why everybody throughout the game freaks out
whenever you actually kill someone with a lethal weapon.
好吧我还要说 这件事我们稍后会聊
Again I know I've said this a thousand times but more on this later.
之后又是一些剧情和对话
There's some cutscenes and exposition
简言之 玩家又遇到了其他角色 比如亡人
but essentially you meet some more characters such as Deadman.
他给你一些药物 要你派送给总统 我猜因为她快死了 该打点止疼药了
You get given drugs to deliver to the president because she's dying I guess, and needs heroin.
于是你开始了派送
And so you deliver them.
你来到了椭圆办公室 但同时这里也是一间医院
You're in the Oval Office, but it's also a hospital at the same time.
和总统交谈中得知她还抚养了你
You talk with the president who it said also raised you.
游戏暗示她是你的母亲 但说得非常模棱两可
It's implied it's your mother but it's also left ambiguous enough that
也可能她只是抚养你长大的女人
it could just be a woman who raised you.
但总之 玩家再次进入一段过场动画
But regardless, you go through the sequence a cutscene plays out
总统解释了你需要帮助他们重新连接世界从而拯救这个世界
as she explains how you need to help them save the world by connecting things I guess.
而这之前总统让其他所有人都离开了房间
While this has happened to the president ask that everybody leave the room
房间内只有山姆和总统在场
so that it's just Sam and the Madam President.
然后她有点急了
And then she kind of freaks out.
她抓着山姆 从床上摔到地上 然后就是史上最蠢的一段演出
She tackles him falling out of the bed in one of the clunkiest and worst blocked scenes
在我看过的全部娱乐节目中 这绝对是最蠢的
I've ever seen in any entertainment media … like ever.
真的 即使你有多喜欢《死亡搁浅》的故事
Seriously, even if you love Death Stranding's story,
这段演出有多烂也没法说吧 真是太……
how can you defend this … like it's … it's so bad.
看看这段吧 是我的游玩实况
Just watch this clip, this is from my roasting video.
我觉得她要死了 但我对灯发誓
Okay clearly she's dying, but I swear to xxx,
她要真死在这个场景我绝对要叫出声
if she dies during this cutscene, I'm gonna scream.
我太讨厌这种巧合了 真的
I hate coincidences like … sweared mother …
喔……天……啥玩意？
Oh Je … what? … What???
她怎么在地上……爬……
Why is she on the floor crowl' …
我了个去……
Ohhhhh oh my god …
我的天 她真死了 我真的……
Oh my go … she died oh I …
我得……我得冷静冷静 可这也太蠢了！
I gotta … I gotta calm down, I know, but it's like so stupid!
我特别讨厌这样的故事
I hate it when stories do this,
告诉你谁谁谁要死了 你去见个面
when they're like a character is dying go meet with them.
等你一见到人 剧情就像《三分半钟》那样
You meet with them and it just so happens during that like three-and-a-half minute time period
话还没说两句人就没了 因为剧情需要这么演……
where you went and said hello, they died, because it's convenient for the story like …
为什么就不能好好说完话 再让她犯个心脏病之类的
Why isn't it that you leave, say goodbye, and then she has a heart attack.
然后……我真的 受不了！
And … I just … come on!
然后……小岛秀夫综合征！
Oh well … then again! Kojima Syndrome!
看评论区吧 肯定有不少病友
Check the comments I'm sure you'll see many people defending it.
总统死后 他们告诉你必须把她的尸体送去火化
So she dies and after this you learned that you need to take her body to the incinerator
防止之前的事情发生
to avoid what happened in the earlier scene.
你把她背起 向焚化厂进发
You load her up and you take her to the incinerator's location.
这段玩着真的很舒服
It's actually a really peaceful sequence.
玩家把总统背起后 会有一条丝带在风中飘荡
After you've strapped her up, there's a little ribbon blowing in the breeze.
随后玩家会穿过一大片葱郁的碎石地
And you're walking across an expansive green pasture covered in rocks,
耳边还会响起平静温和的音乐
as a nice calming piece of music plays.
真的非常令人放松 但别忘了！
It's actually pretty relaxing, but again!
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
人们玩到这是否还会先入为主地认为游戏只是步行模拟器？会
Does it do anything to shake the preconceived notion that this is a walking simulator? No.
当你把总统的尸体带到焚化厂后
Now while you're delivering the president's body to the incinerator
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
他们还让你把BB 就是胸前罐子里的婴儿
you've also been asked to take a BB, or a baby and a jar,
也送到这里 将它销毁
to this location, to have it also decommissioned.
他们并没说太多 只是说它出故障了 无法使用
You're not told a whole lot except that this is malfunctioning and it's no longer in use.
但在山姆马上要执行的时候 BT来了
However before Sam has a chance to do this, BT show up.
你需要用BB逃离这片区域
And you use this BB to escape the area.
又到了小岛秀夫秀缩写的时候了
Again, Kojima loves his acronyms.
而我其实很喜欢这段内容
And I actually really like this sequence.
This is the one moment where the player actually feels as though
there's going to be more to the game than just a walking system.
However it's over before it even begins.
Seriously I was able to get out of here within about thirty seconds.
In my humble opinion, it seems as though
Kojima Productions should have spent a lot more time showing off what the BT system could do,
and how the gameplay could be extremely varied.
But regardless I think this BT sequence is really pretty.
I think it serves a purpose and I really like it so … thumbs up!
You escape, make it back and you learned that you need to
quote-unquote "expand the Chiral Network", to fulfill Bridget's vision for America.
You're also introduced to Amelie which is a character that is … PAINFULLY unlikable
and has less charisma than a summer squash.
I know that this is probably more personal,
but I found her performance is all extremely stiff.
But again, I don't know if this is just her fault for performing poorly,
or if this is a writing issue and came from the direction of Kojima.
Again! Kojima Syndrome!
Now a quick sidebar, the characters are all asking Sam to cross the entire country,
an extremely dangerous post-apocalyptic country mind you, and save it.
而当游戏里其他角色劝我拯救美国的时候 行为简直比《洛基恐怖秀》还僵硬
And while they're doing this, they're all stiffer than me during The Rocky Horror Picture Show.
What's pushing players at this point? What's pushing Sam.
We've been told that we need to help connect America
after a major event known as the Death Stranding.
Okay, we know that Amelie is Sam's sister,
even though they don't seem particularly … infatuated or caring of each other, but … okay.
To me it seems as though the operative question is
whether or not this world, America in this case is worth saving.
Where's the humanity that is worth saving?
And this is actually my biggest problem with Death Stranding the game writ large.
It fails to give the player any clear evidence that the world is actually worth saving
that all of this trouble is worth it.
Now I get it, there are not that many people now that the world has ended, basically.
But still, there are very few moments that attempt to humanize these delivery recipients.
I mean hell, if you're gonna ask the player to go through the trouble
of delivering packages mindlessly back and forth between locations,
it seems like you should at the very least try to emotionally motivate them to do so.
However, all of your interactions with all of the people
that you interact with these deliveries show up as Holograms.
You don't even get to see them in person.
But again was this a result of poor game design,
lazy copy and pasted formatting of locations and interactions?
Or is it a meta discussion on the hopelessness
that people have and how empty the world is without connections?
Again,  Kojima Syndrome.
The clearest example of Kojima seemingly attempting to humanize this world and failing miserably
is when you're delivering things to the scrapper.
You see he has a woman that he loves and that he thinks is dead.
You find out that she's alive
but her performance has got to be the worst I've ever seen in a 3A title.
I'm not joking, I'm not trying to be funny, I'm not trying to be mean, this is just … awful.
And I … I get it, English is probably not her first language,
but this performance … is one of if not the worst I have ever seen.
Truly horrible, nothing personal, it's just that bad, watch.
你受伤了吗？
谢谢你了，布里吉斯。
我不敢相信你还活着。
这是我的台词，傻瓜。
我还以为你已经死了。
我妈妈跟我说你死了。
我一直把它带在身边，从未离身。
但那次袭击之后，它就不管用了。
我想过修好它，让沙子重新流动起来。
但那就更像是……展开新生活。
就像……忘了你。
好了……那我们现在可以共同展开新生活了。
一起向前，你和我，只要你做好准备。
当然准备好了。
我所认识的那个男人才不是收垃圾的。
他是修补的好手……能让废品焕然一新。
收集碎片，再最大限度利用。
这也是我最擅长的。
但我们已经不需要这个了。
Now this could have been a moment to prove to the player that
they're still loving caring people in this world.
Instead, we're left thinking that maybe we should put these people out of their misery
because clearly they're poisoned with arsenic.
Now I know I'm being harsh, but this happens repeatedly throughout the story,
where there's a chance for the small characters to prove that this world is worth saving,
but they universally fail.
Again the question seems to me is the so writing issue on the part of Kojima.
Is it his fault? Is it a directorial fault? Again landing on the shoulders of Kojima.
Or, is it just that their performances are that bad.
With this particular instance I think you could say the performance is just that bad.
But at the same time, Hideo is the one that would presumably have cast this woman in this role.
So again the fault still lands on his shoulders.
Point is I think that this is inexcusably bad.
And whether Kojima was happy with this performance
and this narrative structuring in the way that you interact with these smaller characters,
the blame still lands on Kojima shoulders.
Now thankfully the main cast is phenomenal
and they try very hard to deal with the wordy,
and at times nonsensical script that Hideo threw at them.
Sam, Cliff, Fragile, Mama, Deadman, Heartman, Die-Hardman, Higgs … they're all fantastic.
Pretty much with the exception of Amelie / Bridget I think the main cast is pretty solid.
And it makes sense, they're the main cast for a reason.
But when you're trying to motivate the player to save an entire country
because they want to save the country,
you have to give the player some reason to love and to care about
said country and its inhabitants.
And in my opinion, I know that some will disagree, Death Stranding fails miserably
at humanizing the world that it's trying to convince you to save.
Furthermore, this world is so void of life it's kind of ridiculous.
We see wildlife in the opening sequence of the game as I mentioned earlier.
So we know that it exists in this world
but we never experience it in the world … like …ever … or at least I didn't.
You never see deer, you never see a lot of birds flying through the sky.
You never interact with them in any way.
There are also very few original assets in Death Stranding.
A lot of things are repeated.
From the repeated bunkers, to vehicles, to landscapes, to rock formations, to MULE camps,
everything is just copy and pasted around the map.
Now we'll get into this in detail a lot more later.
Don't worry, I've done a lot of math surrounding the placement of these items,
and it's really telling.
But the point is it begs the question was this developed by a small team
that simply didn't have the manpower to put more stuff into the game,
or was this a budgetary concern, or was it some combination,
or was it part of Kojima's broader vision?
Again, Kojima Syndrome.
Regardless, Sam agrees to help expand the Chiral Network begrudgingly at least
and the mid-game begins after a plethora of tutorial missions that introduce
to you crafting inventory and loadout management, course charting, and much much more.
It's slow but it's probably necessary to be perfectly honest
before releasing the players into the mid-game.
And let me be clear, there's nothing wrong with a long intro.
Sure it can be frustrating especially during repeated playthroughs
but it isn't inherently bad.
Look at Assassin's Creed III, the gameplay has an intro that lasts roughly three hours
before it even gives you control of a basic stripped-down assassin
that it advertised pre-launch.
It's not inherently bad, it's just inefficient.
The only reason efficiency is important
is to convince the aforementioned sceptical players to continue playing.
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
Again look at those two goals I put on screen.
Does a long dry intro achieve either of these? Probably not.
《死亡搁浅》必须证明其拥有有趣的值得游玩的内容
且叙事必须经过深思熟虑 自圆其说
But I didn't want to just take all of this on assumption.
So in the survey that I conducted,
again all of the data is up on Luke Stephens net if you want to check it out yourself,
I asked players who hadn't finished the game at the time of polling,
and 28.5% of them said that they either weren't going to continue playing
or that they were unsure if they would.
That's over one in four players who didn't feel compelled to continue.
Now no matter how you look at that, no matter how you split it,
with a sample size of 2,400 people, that is a straight-up failure of the game's pace and design.
I don't care if you're making a video game, a song, a movie, or a book,
if somebody gets just a couple hours into it just dipping their toes into it,
and over 1 in 4 people are unsure or straight-up reject the idea of continuing, you have failed.
Furthermore, the poll shows that over 36% of players who gave up on the game
had put less than five hours in,
and roughly 66% had played less than 10 hours before stopping.
Sure you can argue that this game simply wasn't meant for them,
or they were never going to enjoy it
no matter how polished or how much they reworked the opening sequence.
But I think the fact that so many players
dropped out in the first few hours of playing the game
shows that something was wrong with the first few hours.
Again these people are paying $60 presumably to play this game.
They put their money on the line,
which by itself lends these opinions credibility, at least in my opinion.
But this brings us to the mid-game, where episodes 5 through 10.
This really is deliveries galore.
You're slowly expanding the map, exploring it, delivering packages to your heart's content.
This is where the game shines.
This is where the gameplay reaches its highest potential.
You unlock all sorts of new tools, vehicles, and things that you can do,
crafting, and much much more.
This was the act of the game that I found myself enjoying the most.
Mostly because I was able to just look forward to making some deliveries and relaxing
as I ran across the open countryside when I got back from a long day.
I racked my brain a lot as to why this was so relaxing to me and why I enjoyed it,
because on its face, it really is pretty simplistic.
Sure you might occasionally encounter some MULEs or BTs
that require some stealth approaches to getting around them.
But writ large, this is just a game about delivering packages from one location to the other.
It is extremely repetitive.
So why did I enjoy it? It was a little baffling to me.
But after a lot of thought I think it's for the same reason that hiking is enjoyable.
Because the game allows you to play it in just passive enough a state
that you can let your mind wander.
You'll find yourself daydreaming about other things as you explore this vast expanse.
And it's relaxing.
Plus it's no mystery that the world of Death Stranding is very beautiful,
especially in a lot of individualized places that are heavily trafficked.
Other less trafficked areas show a significant lack of polish in terms of the graphic fidelity,
but we'll get to that later.
But here I'm actually gonna say something that makes me sound like a fanboy.
And that's that, if you don't see the appeal of Death Stranding's gameplay system,
I think you might need to try it.
Now I'm not saying that you should go out and pay $60 for the game or 40 if it's on sale.
Just to try this, and that if you don't do that your opinion is invalid.
That's not what I'm saying.
What I am saying is that the relaxing nature of Death Stranding's gameplay
is something that you will only experience if you are the one doing it.
In the same way that watching somebody hike isn't satisfying
in the same way that hiking itself is.
If you want to enjoy nature, you have to be the one in it.
If you want to enjoy the world of Death Stranding, you have to be the one exploring it.
This is why for a lot of people who say that they watched people played the game on Twitch
and they don't understand the appeal of the gameplay system even though the streamer enjoyed it.
It doesn't make much sense to me.
Because having played, it it's pretty self-explanatory.
If you want to enjoy the world,
you have to be the one walking through it,
building things in it, driving your motorcycle across it,
you have to do it.
But as to whether or not this is something that's going to appeal to everybody
is a much larger and more difficult question to answer.
And it seems to me that this is something that just isn't going to appeal to everybody,
which is why I said at the beginning you should rely on your instincts.
If the game has repelled you or has been simply uninteresting to you,
it likely isn't going to change that opinion even after 10 hours.
Anyway, throughout the mid-game, you make a ton of deliveries.
You go from location to location, unlocking new areas and meeting new people.
I'm hesitant to use the word "exploring",
even though that's definitely the word that Kojima Productions wants you to use.
For one because in my mind exploring is something that you initiate yourself.
It's not something that you're pushed to do.
Just because a quest can ask you to go from one location to a remote location.
To me that doesn't make you explore those locations.
That's just having you traverse to that location.
Exploring, to me, seems like something that you're going to do for the sake of itself.
An example would be like in Breath of the Wild,
when you find yourself just exploring the world,
going through it, without any quests without anything specifically to do,
just exploring it for the sake of interacting with, and exploring it.
It's adventure in its purest form.
Death Stranding really doesn't encourage you to do this ever.
There are very few secrets, very few things that you can interact with.
And of course there are basically no NPCs
or individuals that you can interact with within the world that make it worth exploring.
But again, I know I've said this a billion times,
we're gonna talk about that more at length in just a few minutes.
But once we plow through all of that, we get to the finale of the game,
or in other words act 3.
The ending that never ends.
This is comprised of episodes 11 through 14.
And it has big reveals, such as Amelie and Bridget being the same person
O … Okay.
You find out that Amelie / Bridget are an extinction entity
and that they can bring on the end of the world which … again, is … okay.
And a lot of things are revealed in this sequence
which to be honest I'm not entirely sure I could explain concisely,
even if I spent a week writing it out.
Chances are if you made it this far into the video,
you probably already have a decent idea of what happens in these final hours.
So … I won't bore you with explaining all of it over again.
The point is that Kojima actually explains a lot of the stuff that goes on
during these sequences.
Now don't get me wrong, I think he could have done it in a tenth the time,
but I'll take what I can get.
There are a few things however I do want to touch on.
For instance, the endless cutscenes at the very end of the game.
The last three or four hours of the game are almost exclusively cutscenes or sequences
within which there is very little player control or interaction.
There's no big gameplay finale other than a large BT fight I guess.
You could say qualifies as a boss fight.
There's also the sequence with Higgs fistfight with him
which is clunkier than almost anything else in the game, it's … really terrible.
But I don't want to address all of that.
I want to talk about the purgatory cutscenes
that Amelie presents to you as you run around the Beach.
Basically you're sent to your Beach with the help of Fragile and everybody else,
and you're just sitting here.
And they play off some credits and it's very peaceful.
And it does feel like purgatory.
Because as you run from one end of the Beach to the other,
you will eventually just get spawned back further.
It's basically the story of Sisyphus and it's actually pretty cool.
I really liked this when I first came to this area.
However after the first 10 minutes or so it starts to get pretty horrible.
Again is this just a poorly designed way of forcing the player
to sit through all of the credits rolling incredibly slowly?
Or, is this some sort of meta discussion of the purgatory
that we all experience when talking about post-credit scenes in games and move …
I don't kno … Point is Kojima Syndrome.
And every time you get transported back after a few minutes,
Amelie will show up and present a cut sequence where she offered some exposition.
Again, I'm glad that all of this is here and that it is expositive
and there are reasons that all of this stuff in this world take place.
But I think it could have been done much more efficiently.
Now before* all of this happened to end up talking with Amelie at length,
and there is what VICE referred to as "the gameplay mechanic of the year".
Thank You Ryan on Twitter for sending me this, I thought this was pretty funny.
Basically Amelie describes that she's going to end the world
and that you can stop her, or you can not, and let it happen.
Of course most players are gonna try to stop her,
but … I don't know. Let me know what you did below
Point is you have a gun, and you can choose to shoot her or you can run after her and hug her,
which is what VICE referred to as the mechanic of the year.
Now she gives a bunch of forewarning and she says
that you should have known how this was going to play out and you know what to do,
because it's the entire point of your journey.
And looking back on it, it makes sense.
She's saying that it's all about connecting people forgiving and embracing others.
So going up to her and hugging her seems like the natural choice.
However, this didn't work for me at all.
And I hesitated, and I even tried to save,
because I decided immediately after she said I know what to do,
to shoot her six times and empty the gun in the back of her head,
which doesn't actually do anything.
At which point I ran up to her to try and punch her
into submission to stop the world from ending.
But that also didn't work.
And instead I was prompted with a hug button.
At which point I pressed hug
and I was made to feel as though I just made an incredible and generous decision
when in reality it was kind of an accident.
Now maybe I'm the weird one here.
But this made the ending sequence really awkward,
Because it feels as though I kind of broke it.
It didn't expect me to shoot her in the back of the head, empty my rounds,
and then go up to her trying to punch her,
only to find out my only option was to hug her.
It was completely unintentional that I saved the world
which made this all VERY FUNNY.
But after all of this, you are saved and the world doesn't explode and everything's okay.
At which point you're eventually saved by all of the people that have helped you this far.
Fragile, Deadman, everybody.
And this is actually what those people off in the distance on the Beach are.
We saw this in a trailer way back in the day a couple years ago
and it seemed as though it was an explicable
how they ever explained these people just floating over the ocean.
But they actually do explain it, and it's kind of cool.
And after this, Sam is saved.
You're brought back to the world of the living.
You go to a presidential inauguration for Die-Hardman, and you get some more exposition.
But eventually you find out after giving the president a pep talk,
that you need to take BB to the incinerator because it passed away.
Or I guess in Deadman's words, it is no longer functioning.
And I'll be honest Kojima actually wrote this pretty well.
The player had built a relationship with BB,
having carried it with him for almost the entire game,
save for the sequence where it's removed from you.
And it's sad to be walking this deceased BB or dis-functional BB, however you want to phrase it,
off to an incinerator, to have it burn.
It's kind of a sorrowful event.
But I will be honest it's actually kind of cool to walk back through where you started.
For those of you not aware, this is the exact same path that you walked with Bridget Strand
when she died to take her to the incinerator.
So effectively the last mission of the game is mirroring order three, which is COOL.
Because that was basically the first order that you completed yourself.
There are no MULEs, no BTs, no threats, you're just hiking along a large green mountainside,
and it's a nice way to finish.
But once you arrive at the incinerator a cutscene begins playing
which you a new perspective on the smaller cutscenes
that you've seen throughout the entire game every time you had a load screen
coming out of a private room for instance.
Now we get a new perspective, and we see all of these sequences play out in order.
And it's actually pretty heartbreaking.
This is the place where Mads Mikkelsen actually earns his game award for best performance.
He really nails it here.
It's beautiful, it's sweet, it's sad, it's endearing, it's … everything.
It's incredibly emotional and I really enjoyed this.
But after all of this ends and you learned that the BB was Sam,
and that Clifford was just trying to correct his mistakes from his past.
Everything comes back into the world of the living.
And you realize that Lou has been taken out of the pod and is now cradled in Sam's hands.
He's frantically trying to revive her doing everything that he possibly can to wake her up.
However, nothing seems to work, and he eventually gives up, cradles her as he begins to cry.
At this point after a brief beat, you start to hear Lou crying.
洛！
She's back.
Sam is stunned and holds her in unparalleled jubilation
as a bunch of BTs watch them from the background which is actually pretty cool
because it seems as though this is what has broken the cycle of all of these BBs,
having their souls effectively destroyed in the incinerator.
Holding Lou, Sam walks out of the incinerator into the open air,
and it's actually raining,
although the timefall doesn't seem to be having any sort of effect.
It's just normal rain.
Furthermore there is a full rainbow behind them which is extremely bright.
And also shows the color blue
which is something that none of the other rainbows in the game show.
Now what does all of this mean?
Well it seems as though the Death Stranding has officially come to a close.
And BB's revitalization has effectively restored the stability of humanity … or … something.
However I will be honest this is so vague
that there are probably a million different ways to interpret it.
And it's not particularly important
because everyone will have their own interpretation which is kind of the point.
What I will say is that it's a very calming peaceful and emotional end
even if I don't completely understand what's going on.
Why was BB able to be restored even though necrosisation was starting to set in.
BB was clearly dead, what brought her back?
Why does the timefall all of a sudden end at this point?
Why is blue all of a sudden present in the rainbow just because a baby came back to life?
I'm not … entirely sure …
But again that's probably not the point.
I would be interested however in hearing your theories as to
what exactly happened when BB was saved here.
I'm sure some of you have thought this through and have a reasonable explanation.
I would love to hear it below.
And then the actual credits roll.
And after all of that happens, we are greeted with episode 15 prompted up to us,
and a quick reading that shows two weeks before.
And this is what I meant earlier when I said that chapter 15 is basically indefinite.
It goes on forever even though it's just two weeks before the presidential inauguration.
This is effectively Death Stranding's endgame state.
It goes on forever and it will allow the player to continue making deliveries,
five-star locations, find and hunt down all of the memory chips,
and complete any other things that they might have left undone.
Now overall the story while it is kind of bizarre and crazy,
it is thought through, and it does have justifications and rules that govern it,
which is what I said at the beginning I was looking for.
However there are a couple of missed opportunities
I can't help to wonder why Kojima didn't explore more.
They might have been that it just felt like it wasn't focused,
or it might have been something that never occurred to him, I'm not entirely sure.
Specifically something such as the discussion that has to do with BB's and slavery.
This is briefly touched on but it's not really elaborated upon.
Specifically, babies come from mothers who died while pregnant,
which is why those mothers are called still mothers.
There are also other times that this concept is applied within the world of Death Stranding,
such as with mama, who we know was to give birth
but was trapped in rubble after the Death Stranding
which resulted in the baby becoming caught
between the world of the living, and the Beach, or the world of the dead.
This is of course why BBs are able to detect BTs
and can show them to the operator that has them strapped to their bellies.
Now while Kojima does have a lot of writing in here,
that discusses the inherent value of human life even as a baby,
he never really touches on the idea
that you are literally taking an independent human as prisoner,
and you're going to dispose of them once they're no longer useful
As Deadman says, it's a tool.
因为我和它是搭档啊。
“搭档”？
山姆，BB是个工具，不是人类。
它是桥梁吗？是。是婴儿吗？不是。
And they don't really explore this very much.
They do touch on the idea pretty aggressively
that the BB is becoming sentient, the BB is becoming human.
And it's going to start growing like a regular human very soon.
This is of course why Deadman has to take the BB away from the player
roughly halfway through the game in order to perform an operation
to separate it from the humanity
that's pulling it out of the world of the dead and closer to the world of the living.
And this is what partially makes me think that Kojima had thought of this
and simply decided to focus on the more pro-life discussion having to do with the BB's,
the idea that these infants still have value as human life even though they're just infants.
They're contained within a tank.
They don't have much of anything by way of autonomy, but they still are valuable.
So it could be that Kojima just decided
that the discussion on slavery would have been too much and wasn't worth pursuing.
Or maybe he just didn't think to add it in, I'm not entirely sure.
Either way, it could have been cool to see him explore the idea
of BBs being enslaved to a more powerful master,
and not having any way of fighting it or claiming their own independence.
I'm not really sure let, me know your thoughts below.
Another thing that struck me is weird throughout the course of the story
is the fact that they break the fourth wall all the time.
And I'm not entirely sure why.
Now of course you could say that this is just Kojima style and that's what he likes to do.
So to judge it is simply unfair.
However as I discussed earlier, the world that Death Stranding is taking place within
has to be consistent and it has to live by its own rules, preferably, at all times.
And for the most part it succeeds in this.
The game seems to want players to be immersed at all times
with the realistic graphics and the traversal system being very realistic.
But at the same time, Sam breaks the fourth wall constantly.
Though, in fairness, it is mostly relegated to the private room.
It feels weird.
Ride with Norman Reedus AMC as an ad on the bathroom while he poops,
it's really weird and out of place, I'm not really sure why it's here.
Plus if you leave the camera sitting on him too long, he'll gesture at you,
and he'll stare at you, make funny faces at you.
It's fun, but it's weird.
If I were directing the game, I would have cut all of this.
Because in my opinion, it's not worth the trouble.
It pulls the player out of the game.
And while you are in a private room when these things happen,
I don't think that that's an excuse.
Though I will admit that this is probably a matter of personal preference.
Some people will mind it such as myself,
others don't mind that at all and some I'm sure really enjoy it.
Now of course these fourth wall breaks and these think outside the box mechanics
are nothing new to Kojima.
As somebody sent me on Twitter,
Metal Gear Solid has a sequence like this when snake is fighting Mantis.
You actually have to change the port that the controller is connected into
in order to complete the game and continue on, which is kind of funny, imagine doing that today.
It's weird, because Kojima talks about being an artistic purist
and describes how he thinks Americans don't have artistic sensibilities.
But he's the one putting paid product placement in his games with
the Monster Energy drinks and the AMC ads.
Can you imagine what people would say
托德·霍华德：贝塞斯达游戏工作室总监和执行制片人
if Todd Howard started putting Tesla ads in Fallout or Elder Scrolls.
People would rightly lose their minds.
The only reason Kojima gets a break, is again, Kojima Syndrome.
Now don't get me wrong, fourth wall breaks can be done well, even in narrative focused games.
Look at The Lost Legacy tower sequence for instance.
Here there's a tower you can find
and there's a very narrow route that you can climb up optionally.
And if you get to the top of it and you hang out there for an extended period of time,
Chloe will start to tease you, and will actually break the fourth wall
However, things like the otter hat that you get from Conan O'Brien within Death Stranding
柯南·奥布莱恩：美国脱口秀主持人、喜剧演员、
作家、制作人、配音演员
游戏中“角色扮演家”的演员
are somehow both weird and perfectly in place, it's really bizarre.
But you can't help but feel as though Kojima didn't take all of this very seriously
which I also too appreciate, I mean their video games.
And all customization is like this from changing paints to glasses, to Otter Hoods.
It's all fun.
And though it doesn't mean much in the story it's a welcome addition
even if it doesn't make sense in terms of
Bridges having standardized uniforms that everybody is expected to wear.
But the point is, while the fourth wall breaks may bug me,
I can understand why they might not bother other people.
I think it is a matter of personal preference.
It just bothers me, though it might not bother you.
But with all of that, let's discuss the gameplay,
and the systems that make Death Stranding work.
So obviously a lot of people have said that Death Stranding's gameplay loop
is quote-unquote "BORING".
To determine if this is true,
let's look at what your average mission is going to be comprised of.
Let's start with story missions.
In this case we're going to look at a random order in the mid-game.
Now in this order we have 60 minutes to collect medical devices
from one character in the mountainous area
and then deliver them back to the area where we accepted the order.
In other words, a fetch quest.
Now this is actually one of the more elaborate order types that you can get
because it involves multiple stops.
Simpler orders just give you items with the destination.
So you accept the order and get told that you need to deliver the items quickly.
And furthermore that the items that you're picking up are classified as "fragile",
which means that you can't drop the packages, often you can't go in water, etc.
Basically you have to be extra careful.
You select your gear and load Sam up
with any ladders, PCCs, climbing anchors, extra boots or weapons that you may need.
Then you set out and you begin hiking.
In this case I'm not going to use any vehicles because we're going through a mountainous area
and they aren't particularly useful in this rocky snowy area.
This is what would usually be considered a more difficult mission.
Specifically because it's in the snowy mountainous area.
Not once in my over 100 hours with Death Stranding
did I encounter a mission where I failed the time limit.
The only time I had any difficulty was when the items were fragile,
or when I was completing multiple orders all at once,
loading up with four or five orders at a given time.
And so the way that the game dynamically alters the difficulty
is with the routes that they'll have you do.
This is why long routes tend to reward you with more likes
and routes that go into the mountains also do the same.
Now you can unlock certain items that makes node-traversal and mountain traversal easier,
for instance, lots of ladders, climbing anchors that you can level up,
power gloves, the all-terrain exoskeleton,
and of course the zip-lines which you can use to set up routes
after you've initially explored them.
So with all this in mind I continued hiking, eventually I reached a cliff top,
where I could have just dropped a ladder or a climbing anchor to descend and then cross by foot.
But I happen to know that this area is infested with BTs.
So I decided to build a zip-line which allowed me to completely skip this area,
which effectively skips five to ten minutes of navigation.
Don't worry, we're gonna go into a lot of detail with these zip-lines in just a bit.
I reach to the bottom and continue hiking.
Eventually I pick up the items, and then the entire process repeats as you're return.
Now when you drop off the items you are graded on the condition that the packages are in.
This can be both the quality of the outside container,
in addition to the quality of the internal item
which can experience damage if you aren't careful.
For instance, if you fall off of a ladder, you'll fall, take damage,
and the packages will be worth less when they're eventually delivered.
There are however ways to deal with this.
For instance with the timefall shelters if you stay in them
and especially once they're upgraded,
they'll actually repair your items as you stand underneath them.
There of course also the cargo repair sprays which you can carry on your back.
But this is basically it.
There isn't much more to the gameplay system other than this.
I know it may come as a surprise, but Death Stranding is not a third-person shooter.
It's also not a monster fighting focused game,
which means that all of the combat encounters that you'll experience are pretty clunky.
And I don't know about you but every time I went to one of these flashback sequences with cliff,
I was really excited, because they're very visually impressive.
You get to travel back to World War one or World War two or Vietnam.
It's very interesting visually.
But once you actually engage with the gameplay, you realize that it's just a shooting gallery,
and it's not a particularly difficult one.
Even on the hardest possible difficulty, it doesn't change much.
Really, as long as you're keeping cover and shooting the enemies when they appear,
which is all the time, you're gonna be fine.
Now as you would expect with the story, the game heavily encourages
you to make sure that you're never using actually lethal means of taking down opponents,
that you're only using non-lethal means.
For this reason, they include non-lethal assault rifles,
which basically completely negates the difficulty that would have been put in place
by having a non-lethal requirement.
Basically, these are still guns, they just don't finish the opponent in a death state.
Instead, they're in an incapacitated state, which allows you to just continue on your merry way.
I don't know why they did this because it seems to undermine their own pursuit
of making sure that the player needs to take a step above everybody else.
The player needs to have non-lethal means of interacting with enemies such as the MULEs
because they're better than the MULEs.
But instead, you just use assault rifles that incapacitate them,
which completely eliminates any gameplay difficulty that would have been there
as a result of taking a stealth approach or a peaceful approach.
But rest assured, this idea of the game undoing itself
is something we're going to talk about much more in just a moment.
But while discussing these deliveries, it's also important to discuss the map design.
Now in my mind this is probably the most important game design element that is here.
The mechanics of walking balancing, and using vehicles can all be fantastically well-designed.
But if the world itself is not worthy of being explored, nobody's gonna care.
Now like I said before,
there are very FEW inherent reasons to explore the world of Death Stranding.
There are no major secrets, no NPCs,
and only a very few select secret locations and items to find
that make the player excited and wanting to explore more.
For instance, in Red Dead Redemption 2,
there are all sorts of dynamic encounters that you can either choose to interact with or not.
But the world is littered with them which means that every time you go out to explore the world,
you're going to find something new and interesting.
It's one of the reasons the world of Red Dead Redemption 2 feels so alive.
My favourite example in RDR2 would of course be the incestuous siblings,
where I was just riding through the map and I encountered this brother and sister
who were … very close.
They try to kill you and a bunch of really funny and interesting stuff goes down.
I won't spoil it, but I highly recommend hunting them down if you ever in that world.
Or another example would be the puzzles and encampments
that are hidden all over Breath of the Wild.
They make the world worth exploring for its own sake.
Now there are things in Death Stranding to find, I can already hear you saying it.
Things such as the memory chips and the hot springs, but I don't think these actually qualify.
And I'll explain why in just a moment.
The main thing to understand is that the world of Death Stranding
isn't particularly well crafted, at least in my opinion.
And I have a lot of math to back this up.
In fact, it seems to me that this map was dynamically generated
with very little input on the part of the development staff,
and they just went with it once they found a random arrangement that they liked.
Once they had this, they decided to scatter all of the flat areas with boulders and streams.
And I have to ask why.
Seriously, you will be hard-pressed to find any stretch of grass
that's more than a hundred yards.
These rocks after all take a positive action to create.
Somebody has to put them there.
So clearly there must be some reason as to why that individual was instructed to put them there.
And to me it seems pretty clear.
They're just there to break up the monotony, and to make traversing a conscious activity.
And they also are there to make vehicles far more difficult to use.
This is because if vehicles become too useful,
the deliveries cease being an engaging experience
where you're engaging with the world looking around and interacting with it,
and slowly begin to be a matter of tedium.
After all, if all you need to do to make a delivery is hop in a car
and drive from one location to the other,
why do you need to build and upgrade the roads?
Why do you need to build zip-lines?
There would be no reason to,
which is why you have to drop boulders on the ground
to make cars and motorcycles just annoying enough to use
that it would be more useful to spend the time upgrading roads and zip-lines.
Now for those of you who followed this channel for a while or have seen to my older videos,
you will know that I do a series where I break down the density of a game world.
Basically I will take a selection of gameplay that's two or three hours long,
and I will chart out how much time is in between moments of interest.
How I define moments of interest is something that changes my thought process.
So if I'm exploring the world,
and I see an animal run across the screen in Red Dead Redemption 2,
something that catches my attention and changes my thought process, that qualifies.
But some things such as just avoiding a tree while riding a horse wouldn't qualify,
because that's something I can do passively.
Now granted this is an incredibly subjective way of measuring these types of things,
which is why it's something that I do myself.
I don't use data from other people, or other people's gameplay.
This is only from me, so it would seem in my estimation
that that alone would serve as a fairly good control.
Now all of this started back with The Witcher 3.
The designer said that they were aiming for anywhere between 30 and 40 seconds
between moments of interest.
If they hit that number, then they would know that the world was dense enough
to hold players attention while feeling expansive.
And in my testing, The Witcher 3 does in fact adhere to that rule.
And I've tested a lot of games in this way.
Zelda: Breath of the Wild, Skyrim, Fallout: New Vegas, all of them.
I even calculated this for Red Dead Redemption 2
which had the longest time between moments of interaction.
But the quality of those interactions were much higher.
For this reason I decided to make these same calculations for Death Stranding.
Because it seems to me, that this world doesn't feel anywhere near as alive or interesting
as the world of Red Dead Redemption 2, Zelda: Breath of the Wild, or even Fallout: New Vegas.
So I broke the map into three broad areas where a lot of orders are going to be taking place.
Snowy areas, greenery laced late game areas,
and stream heavy areas where vehicles are usually going to be used,
but their batteries may drain quickly.
For these I used roughly two hours of gameplay footage,
timed out the moments, in between moments of interest,
and then I paused the timer whenever I was interacting or dealing with something
that engaged my interest.
So for instance if I encountered a MULE that started attacking me,
I would pause the timer while I dealt with that threat.
And once I began exploring again with a clear mind, I started the timer.
And this is the data I collected, now do you notice anything?
It looks completely randomized.
There are a couple of exceptions here and there,
such as when I was navigating a very dense area and it required a lot more of my attention.
But broadly, this is incredibly random.
In fact looking at the standard deviations and the kurtosis of the charts,
it seems to me it is randomized.
This is something I haven't seen in any of the aforementioned open-world games.
All of those had very intentionally placed items and dynamic interactions.
They were placed and designed in such a way that they would intrigue the player,
and they would be paced out in such a way
that the player would always have something tickling their fancy.
However, the world of Death Stranding is completely randomized.
Everything here looks as though,
it was dynamically placed with almost no effort put on it from the developers.
There's no careful crafting of routes,
there's no trail building to give players a clear way of going,
there's nothing like that in this world.
It literally looks as though it was just randomly generated and left alone.
Again I can't express how insane this is for a $60 title in 2019.
In my opinion, it's straight-up unacceptable.
Now I can't help but also feel as though
the world of Death Stranding is made in a much more realistic way.
In other words, it is random.
It isn't carefully crafted by developers to enhance the experience of the player.
But the point is, we're playing video games here.
This is in the real world.
And if you're going to try to improve the experience for the player,
you are going to need to enact some positive actions.
But even with this data staring them in the face,
I guarantee you there will be people who will defend this.
They will say that this more realistic way of designing the world was intentional,
and it's good, because the world itself is more realistic.
And exploring it and navigating it is more realistic,
which is the point of Death Stranding blah-dee-bloo-d'blah-blah …
Again, Kojima Syndrome.
This is straight-up unacceptable in a AAA game in 2019 when this released.
It's not good, this is laziness personified.
And frankly, this explains why the world does feel so empty.
The design wasn't carefully crafted or arranged.
Sure, MULEs and BT zones are permanently placed and those don't change.
But rocks, ledges, routes and everything else in the world that you explore
seems straight-up randomly placed.
I also did some further calculations on the placement of the items
that you can find throughout the world.
Such as other zip-lines the players have crafted, generators, and the like,
and believe it or not these are also pretty much random.
There are a couple of constraints that seem to be put in place
such as a limitation on how many of a single item can be in a given area.
So for instance you can only have one online generator
within a certain radius of another generator.
But in general, this is all randomly spawned in with the limitation of chiral volume
and those distance limitations that I just mentioned.
This is laziness, and I don't know how anybody could defend it.
Again the question is is, this just a team that was too small?
Or was incapable technologically of dealing with this?
Couldn't craft it more carefully?
Or maybe they just decided it wasn't worth crafting it more carefully?
Who can say?
Whatever the excuse, in practice, the design of the world is random, and it's lazy.
Now speaking of Chiral bandwidth, I have to ask, why? Why is this a thing?
Chiral bandwidth is the system, by which the game determines
how many of a certain item or a collection of items you can craft.
Want to build a zip-line network that's massive and expansive and spans the whole map?
Too bad! Because you have Chiral bandwidth to adhere to.
This is basically their version of a carry weight limit,
for items you need to craft, even though there also is a physical carry weight limit,
but you get what I'm saying, it's stupid.
It's just a way of controlling density and increasing tedium.
If you want to build a bunch of zip-lines,
you have to go delete other zip-lines in order to build new ones.
The question is whether this was a technical limitation?
Something where they couldn't handle more of a certain item in the world
or if it was a design choice? Again, Kojima Syndrome.
There were many times when I was building a massive zip-line Network
and I was limited because of this bandwidth.
Now sure, as you upgrade certain areas and new 5-star new locations
you will increase the bandwidth that you're playing with.
But it's never unlimited, and you never have the ability to build to your heart's content.
There is always this arbitrary limitation and it is very frustrating.
Now it seems to me that this was probably put in place to make you reliant on other players.
In other words, if you can't build an unlimited number of zip-lines,
then you're going to have to rely on online generated zip-lines as well.
And other things in the game do this as well.
They make you reliant on other players and their work.
Examples being exoskeletons having batteries,
motorcycles and trucks all needing batteries as well.
In order to charge these up, you need generators.
And dynamically in the world there are many online generators placed in highly trafficked areas.
This is something that makes you feel as though
you need other people in order to continue exploring
even though you could have just charged it up yourself with a generator you built,
it makes you feel as though you're all working together,
which is a cool mechanic to have,
and it does work in making you feel as though you're all working together.
But there is a side effect to this mechanism,
and that's specifically that these batteries just feel tedious.
Especially when you consider how small the charge on these batteries actually are
even in the long-range version of the vehicles.
Building generators for these just feels like busywork, it's not actually fun.
Let me share with you the exact moment
I was completely fed up with batteries and that system within this game.
I was driving this truck with a huge amount of cargo loaded in the back.
I dropped by one location, I loaded it up,
fully charged it, and then head out onto the plains.
And this is a futuristic truck with a fully charged battery.
But this thing has an operating distance that is so low,
it would make a first-generation Tesla blush.
Seriously, this is where I started … and as I drive, and drive, and drive, and drive,
not even going very far … this is where the battery dies … in the middle of the stream.
The car immediately starts freaking out, it pushes me out,
and then, instantly, the car disappears and all of my cargo floats downstream.
And this was so much cargo I couldn't possibly load it up onto my back.
And it all drifted out into the water, and was ruined.
This was well over a thousand likes, instantly lost and several deliveries instantly failed,
due to a stupid mechanism just designed to make you engage in this tedious gameplay cycle
of building generators to charge batteries,
to get to another generator to charge your battery, so you can move on.
In no way is this realistic.
And that's the other question, if this world is designed to be realistic,
and that's your excuse as to why the world design is so crappy,
then why are batteries and things like this so clearly gamified
in order to make you engage in the gameplay system?
It's not consistent.
If you're going to make the gameplay systems realistic and lifelike, do it.
Don't do this half-assed thing, otherwise it just ends up being frustrating,
and forcing the player to wonder whether or not you had any idea what you were doing.
Now another feature of the world are the memory chips.
There are 56 of these and they're hidden in very random places with almost no visual cues.
Now the first time you hear about these
is when you receive an email in Chapter 3 from a character named Nick Easton.
In it he describes a quote-unquote "weird glowing thing"
that he wants you to find in Capital Knot City's isolation ward.
And these emails are actually the only thing that pushed you towards finding these chips.
It's not really a concern in the main story.
Now I ran around for hours and hours collecting these.
Even the one in Higgs' secret room that doesn't unlock
until after fragile deals with him … on the Beach.
And the question is whether or not these are busy work just designed to pad out a platinum run
or if these are placed in the world as a reason for you to explore it,
and to hike through, trying to find every single one of them.
Now to me it seems pretty clearly that it's the former, not the latter.
And to prove this I'm going to show you some examples.
These are some of the more commonly collected ones.
So if you've yet to find all of them, don't worry,
you can still hunt them down and have a good time, for what it's worth.
When you go to the weather station, there's one, placed on a concrete ledge.
Okay you run past this, frequently enough, I think I'm fine with this one.
This one, however, is along the red wall.
It's not an area you would ever be running by.
There's no reason for you to explore this area.
And even once you get there, it hides very very well.
It's hidden in the truck bed, of this area, you have no reason to go to.
This one I'm less okay with.
And it doesn't seem as though it's hidden in a way that encourages you to explore the map.
It's hidden in a way, that encourages this busywork type of gameplay.
This is another one that I'm actually okay with.
It's hidden in an underpass by Mama's base.
This is something that I did stumble on too while exploring.
I didn't have to read any email cueing me to this area.
So obviously I'm okay with this one.
This is one I'm not okay with, it's on the hood of a semi Shore.
It's outside of an area you're going to be trafficking fairly frequently,
but you can't normally climb onto vehicles.
You have no reason to ever climb onto a vehicle.
So the only reason you would hop up on this is if you scanned it,
happen to spot it, and jumped up to grab it.
There's no reason for the player to be looking up here or looking for memory chips in this area.
This is something that you would just stumble onto, or would find if you were cued on to it.
There's this one in the back corner of the loading zone room.
It's just sitting on the floor.
Now fair enough, if you go back here, you're going to spot it, so it's fairly easy to find.
However, the player has no reason to ever go back into one of these areas.
It's just placed here, and you're expected to figure that out for reasons,
even though there's never anything else
placed in these back corners in any of the other loading zones.
There's this one in the snow field, just sitting on top of a collapsed pillar.
This is one that you would probably find during normal gameplay,
especially because this is a BT heavy area,
and this is a zone where you're going to be crouching and stealth in your way through.
So I'm actually ok with this one, this one makes sense.
This one's in a cave and this cave is actually marked with a ton of signs as a timefall shelter.
So it's also likely that you would probably encounter this one
through regular gameplay, even though I didn't.
But the one I like by far, the most, is the one hidden in Higgs' secret room.
This is in the top right corner of the central zone of the map.
It's basically Higgs' center of operations.
It's a really cool hidden area, that I like a lot.
This is really cool that they included this here,
even if some of the quotes scribbled on the wall are kind of … funny and … weird.
I'll just say it again, I really like this.
And I really wish there were more things like this, hidden and scattered throughout the map.
If the map were littered with things such as this,
the player would have a reason and an excuse to explore for the sake of exploring
without any deliveries strapped to their back.
Just going through the world for the sake of interacting with it.
But at last, as far as I'm aware, this is the only thing like it in the game.
Now it's pretty clear to me that these are supposed to be hunted down
with emails that you receive in the game, which is obviously true.
Because many of these chips won't actually spawn
until you've received a given email describing them.
So clearly they want you to be interacting with the emails, and using the emails to find them.
For example, the memory chip The Walk doesn't actually unlock
until you've leveled up the First Prepper,
one of the most isolated individuals in the entire game.
And because you're supposed to rely on these emails,
I think it's fair to say that these are here to encourage you to read through the emails,
not here to encourage you to explore the world.
The last thing that I can think of that would encourage you
to explore the world for the sake of exploring it would be the hot springs.
These are something that are briefly mentioned and they're kind of cool.
Basically there's six by my count in the middle zone alone.
And they allow you to hop in.
And there's regenerative qualities to them.
And … though it is cute because you hop in and you chill with your BB,
I never really felt the need to use these or hunt them down intentionally.
When I encountered one I would hop in,
but that was really the only time I ever use them.
Again, I'm glad they're, here but this is by no means a reason to explore the map.
It's just six things that sit on the map, that are kind of fun when you find them.
But you'll forget about them within 50 feet.
The point of all of this is to say that the world design of Death Stranding
is so incomprehensibly bad.
I don't really know how to explain it other than pure laziness.
Hell, my degree is in Corporate Finance.
I'm not a specialist in game design, but all of this is pretty basic to me.
And the fact that Kojima Productions can't manage to follow
any of the basic practices of AAA open-world game development.
It's completely baffling to me.
If you have an explanation for it, I would love to hear it down in the comment section below.
对《死亡搁浅》的另一常见批评之一是人们认为游戏玩法过于重复
Regardless, one of the other common accusations that's levied against Death Stranding
is the idea that the gameplay is purely repetitive
而游戏的这一特点会让玩家失去游玩动力
and there's no reason to engage with it because of its repetitious nature.
And on the macro level I think that is fair enough,
which is why I ran through the basic outline of a quest earlier in this section.
However, on the micro level, is where I would slightly disagree.
Because while you are going to be repeating
the same basic macro process of delivering items from one location to the other,
you are going to be using a plethora of different tools in order to achieve this end.
Whether you're walking, using motorcycles,
or trucks, ladders, climbing anchors, bridges, or zip-lines,
pretty much across the board you're going to be using a plethora of different tools.
All told it is repetitive in the purest sense of the word, but what game isn't.
In Red Dead Redemption you're going to be engaging in gun firefights and riding your horse.
That's pretty much it.
In The Witcher 3, you're going to be talking with people and sword-fighting.
Sure occasionally you're also going to be crafting things
but that's also true of Death Stranding and even with Red Dead Redemption 2.
Every game has a set of gameplay mechanics that they're going to repeat, rinse,
repeat, rinse, repeat, over and over and over again.
After all it's kind of the definition of a video game.
To me, the problem isn't with the fact that the gameplay system is repetitious.
The problem is that the orders while being repetitious require you
to go over areas that you've traversed time and time and time again.
It ceases to be interesting after the first few times,
especially once you've built items that help you get over this,
such as ladders, climbing anchors, bridges, or zip-lines.
They completely negate the need to engage with the other elements of the gameplay loop,
and end up just turning this whole process into a tedious one,
instead of one of exploration and adventure.
This is especially an issue
because you are encouraged to craft a ton of items
and to load up way more than you likely need for a given mission.
I found myself many many times
trying to use all of my ladders and climbing anchors that I brought with me,
just because I had crafted too many,
and I didn't want to have a back fully-loaded of things that I wasn't using.
So I would make sure that I would drop all the ladders,
all the climbing anchors, and everything that I had carried,
to make sure that they were getting used.
If anything I ever built was interfering with the Chiral density
or was making it so that the Chiral bandwidth was overloaded, I would just delete them.
And many times the game actually does this for you,
which is why the timefall is kind of a cool gameplay mechanic.
Because it's a reason in game for items to deteriorate,
and get deleted effectively after a certain amount of time,
which forces you to go back over those areas,
rebuild the things that you had previously put there.
But I don't think timefall degrades these items fast enough
for you to feel as though you need to constantly be up keeping on all of the things
that you've put into the world.
Furthermore I was almost never limited by resources when I was crafting these things.
After all, resources tend to be stored in the locations at which you're crafting items,
so there's rarely ever a time where you find yourself short.
Only when building Road and bridges did I notice a need for extra materials.
But after a few quick trips to a MULE-camp and back to the home base to extract materials,
all of this was fixed.
I experimented with some higher difficulty options to see
if this would make item spawns or material spawns much lower to make this much more involved,
to make it so you couldn't craft 4 ladders, 2 anchors, 2 boots, 2 gloves, 5 guns and 3 vehicles,
all at the same time without ever feeling the impact of it.
And I'm sorry to report,
the difficulty really only affects the combat and the damage that you receive and deal out.
It doesn't actually change much of anything as far as I can tell
in terms of item spawns or anything like that.
Furthermore, you can also repair items and packaging.
If a road is degrading or if a bridge is breaking down,
you can just repair it with some extra items.
Though I will be honest I never felt the need to do this in all my time with the game
because the crafting cost of a brand new one was so low.
But now we get to the point where Death Stranding starts to kind of undo itself and unravel.
And this is my biggest late-game problem with Death Stranding
in addition to the poor world design
and also the lack of any sort of emotional tied to the world you're trying to save.
You see the gameplay system is fairly sparse to begin with, which isn't inherently bad.
After all anyone can boil anything down to its simplest parts.
You can say that Disco Elysium is just a walking simulator,
or that Grand Theft Auto V is just a crime simulator.
In my eyes you can turn anything into a game as long as that thing is fun and fulfilling.
Hell, you can even make a farming game fun and relaxing.
So, my problem isn't with simplistic gameplay systems.
It's with systems that undermine themselves on a fundamental level.
And I know that this is a big accusation to levy against Death Stranding
and I don't make it lightly, so allow me to argue my point.
The zip-line and the leveling system.
You see the zip-line in my opinion is far too useful.
It makes all other traversal techniques and mechanics completely obsolete.
You see once you set up a few zip-line routes,
you have no need to ever craft ladders,
to ever craft climbing anchors, all-terrain exoskeletons, it's all useless.
Because once you craft a couple of zip-lines at the highest peak
and build your network out from there,
you no longer have the need to interact with the lazily designed world.
All you do is dangle by your cuff link as you fly through the sky.
It bypasses all BT interactions, all MULE interactions,
effectively negating the entire gameplay system that they just set up.
And I think Kojima Productions was actually aware of this
and became aware of it at least later in development,
which is why they added the Chiral bandwidth system in in the first place.
Because they realized if they allowed players to just build zip-lines everywhere,
it would completely negate the need for crafting roads, building ladders, bridges, everything.
Now the obvious defense of these zip-lines as they are
is that they're going to force players to appreciate the work of other players
that you're going to use online zip-lines
in addition to the zip-lines your crafting paired with the chiral bandwidth system
This makes sure that you're dependent on other people.
But I would argue that this isn't the case,
because roads which are introduced very early in the game
require so many materials to construct.
They do this job.
Zip-lines are simply too cheap and easy to construct
in order to make you feel truly dependent on other players.
In fact, because the placement of these online zip-lines seems so randomized
as I discussed earlier,
I found myself deleting online zip-lines multiple times
because they were getting in the way of my own zip-line network.
If Kojima really wanted zip-lines to represent the ultimate cooperation between players,
they should have been far more expensive to build, instead of just a level-2-PCC.
In my opinion, the fix to this would be to make roads far more important in the late game,
and to have zip-lines completely cut or made far more expensive,
on the same level of expense as roads.
These things are so cool, fast,
and they bypass so much of the gameplay system just like the roads do,
that they shouldn't be so carelessly added.
This is coming from somebody who has a huge network of zip-line set up
in his safe file of the game.
I love the zip-lines, and I think they're far too useful.
Now I don't know when they added zip-lines to the game.
But it seems to me they were probably added later in development when they realized
that the late-game map was going to be too vertical for roads.
This is likely one of the reasons why roads are discussed constantly
in the first 10 to 15 hours of the game.
And then it seems like everybody forgets about them, and they start talking about zip-lines.
My guess is that this was because they realized roads and mountains don't mix very well,
whereas zip-lines could be the ultimate fix all for navigating over mountaintops.
But to me this is no excuse.
All they had to do was make zip-lines more expensive in terms of materials.
And to make it so … perhaps … they require three players chiral IDs or something to construct.
Point is, there are ways they could have done this,
to make sure that zip-lines weren't too useful,
so that players would continue engaging with the core gameplay loop,
that they had spent 30 to 35 hours engaging with previous.
Now I get it, you're giving players more options more tools to use
in order to engage with the game, I get that.
But if players are given the chance to spam the gameplay loop,
they will, for better, and worse.
And in this case, I think it's for worse.
And again it really seems that Kojima Productions
were all aware of these systems becoming too useful.
They were scared that roads were too useful
which is why they made them incredibly expensive to construct.
They were scared that vehicles were going to be too useful
which is why they scattered almost every square inch of the map
with rocks, and boulders, and rivers,
to make sure that they were just tedious enough to use, that you wouldn't get reliant on them.
This is also why batteries are attached to every useful item in the game
whether their speed exoskeletons, power exoskeletons, or the all-terrain ones.
All because they want you reliant on other players,
and to make sure that you aren't bypassing all of the other gameplay systems.
After all, they could have made a truck or a snowmobile
that made the mountain sections far easier.
But they didn't because those were supposed to be the difficult sections,
which is why it's so strange to me
that the zip-lines completely negate all of the mountain sections
and make them ridiculously easy.
Now in addition to these zip-lines,
the leveling system I think also undermines the gameplay progression,
though I will be honest, in a much lesser degree.
You see every time you level up you can carry more.
You keep your balance better, it increases your stamina, your health, everything.
This is pretty common but it often means
that the game becomes easier to play, the later you get into.
It this is actually one of the major criticisms I made of Assassin's Creed Odyssey
that I made in my ultimate critique of that game, which by the way is just under three hours.
If … you're enjoying this video, I recommend that you check that one out after this as well.
The point is, that as the player becomes more powerful,
they become less reliant on the gear and the items that you have been given,
again, undermining those very items.
Now I want to shift gears a little bit,
and talk about the broader implication of Death Stranding as Kojima described it.
He said the Death Stranding was going to become
and was going to introduce a new type or genre of game.
In my opinion, he didn't do this.
Effectively the idea was that the world was going to be shared,
at least in terms of the items that players will put in the world to share.
Now don't get me wrong, the Chiral Network and shared items are cool,
but it doesn't actually feel like a revolution,
at least I think in the way that Kojima intended.
Sure, it's helpful to have a zip-line already built in an area,
but the developers limited the number of items that can be placed in a particular zone,
so that it never feels particularly crowded.
And in concept, this is pretty simple and straightforward.
It's a world that's shared, but you can't actually see or find other players.
You only see traces of them, which makes you dependent on them.
And the game actually tries to turn this into some sort of profound statement,
but I think it's just an attempt at explaining why other players are absent.
I don't know, you let me know in the comments.
And honestly having this in mind, why not have other players visible and present.
You could give them other skins, so that they don't look like Sam to avoid griefing.
And even have their movements recorded,
and then played back in your world at a later time to prevent griefing nauseam.
This would be similar to what racing games do when you race against your friends
even when they're offline you just play against a ghost of theirs.
This could make it so as you explore the world,
you're actually seeing other Porter's delivering stuff.
And yeah, sure, now there are NPCs
that you occasionally will see walking with weapons and things,
but these are Non-Player-Controlled characters.
These are computer controlled, they are not other players.
And well, yes you can occasionally see a ghost of a player
or signs that other players have left,
this is not anywhere near on the level of having truly interactable players
at least in my opinion.
The point is, they could have fully realized multiplayer systems in Death Stranding,
and it wouldn't have disrupted the story or the gameplay.
So, why didn't they?
Well it could have been technical, it could have been monetarily determined,
it could have been that they didn't want to advertise it as an online game,
it could have been that they were avoiding the PlayStation Plus requirement for online play,
and that would have gone over the line.
Or it could have been simply that Kojima wanted the world to be empty.
Obviously, he stripped it of other life like the birds and the deer that we see in the opening,
so maybe he meant all this to be empty, and lifeless.
Again, Kojima Syndrome.
I think could have really added to the game even just to have AI controlled NPCs
wandering the wastes and delivering packages constantly.
You pass them on trails, you can speak with them, you can trade with them.
They might have a ladder, and you have a climbing anchor.
You need the ladder more, so you trade for it.
It could have made the world feel more alive, again, worth saving.
And this is my primary point of the section.
If this new genre of game is supposed to bring people together,
it's ironic that it's done the exact opposite.
But all of this, thoroughly convinces me that
this game was on a strict budget, and even was rushed out the door.
Allow me to argue my point.
To me it seems pretty clear.
Animals were cut from the game.
They went through the trouble of modeling and animating them for the opening sequence.
They must have been in the game at some point.
And they were completely cut later in development
when it became clear that they were going to be too tedious to place carefully in the world,
or perhaps they were making the world feel too alive, and it didn't feel like an apocalypse.
Either way, it looks as though they were cut.
And PC interactions after orders are almost all holographic and look objectively terrible.
These are all copy and pasted with different skins effectively and new voice actors,
but they're all the same.
Bridges and Fragile housings buildings and environments
are all copy and pasted across the entire game.
Very few vehicles, especially considering the variability of locations,
snowy areas, rocky areas, River covered areas they're all highly variable.
And the vehicles that are there to offer transportation across these
are nowhere near as variable.
There are areas on the outskirts of the map in the central area
which are all glitchy and frankly terrible.
It shows that they put a lot of effort
in polishing the central areas in the heavily trafficked areas, which is fair enough.
But it shows that there's a real lack of polish all over this game.
You just have to know where to look.
And all of this is too bad because it does really make you wonder
what Death Stranding would have looked like
if Kojima were given another year or so to work on it and a lot more money.
But that brings us to the question of Kojima's strengths and weaknesses,
which, no doubt, there are plenty.
I figured what better way
to end this critique of Death Stranding than to discuss the man himself.
You see Kojima does whatever he wants whenever he wants to.
That's kind of the whole point of him leaving Konami,
is that now he is completely free.
However after playing through Death Stranding, I can't help but feel as though
he desperately needs a dramaturg, or a co-director, to keep him in check.
I feel as though through the course of this video I've outlined a lot of reasons
why Kojima needs to be restrained
and needs to have somebody to deal with him in a much more mature way.
Because I honestly don't think he knows when to stop or when he's being ridiculous.
I could point to things such as the fourth wall breaks,
all of the product placement, for AMC, and Monster Energy drinks.
There's a lot of really bad plot twists and a lot of the writing in here is so wordy.
It's hard to even follow what Kojima is trying to communicate.
Now I took a playwriting class a couple of years ago, and it was really interesting.
But one of the things that the teacher said on the first day of class
was that new writers tend to write A LOT,
whereas experienced writers tend to write WELL.
And I couldn't help but feel as though Kojima is a new writer.
He seems to just throw all of the spaghetti at the wall just hoping something sticks.
So instead of writing a monologue that's three sentences long,
he'll write one that's 15 minutes long,
and hope that you get something more significant from that.
I think it shows a certain amount of insecurity in his writing
that he feels as though he can't communicate in as short a time as a lot of other writers could,
such as Neil Druckmann, who wrote The Last Of Us, Uncharted 4,
and is currently writing and directing The Last Of Us Part II.
Now listen, I loved PT, and that was all Kojima.
But it was a humble and confident Kojima.
It wasn't Kojima with something to prove having left to Konami.
And to be honest, I like humble Kojima more than this new one.
Now in that survey, I mentioned at the top of this video where over 2400 of you responded.
I asked you guys, what you thought of Hideo Kojima.
And many of you had some pretty varied opinions of him.
Here's a selection of some of the ones I thought were interesting and funny.
"He's an artistic genius who can't tell a coherent story."
I think he's innovative and incredibly talented,
but he fails to see criticism for what it is,
and his fans think he can do no wrong.
He needed others to reign in his vision to make it more appealing.
He knows exactly what he wants to make and he doesn't waver.
He's an innovator, but not a hands-down genius.
He presents the most unique ideas for world building and characters,
despite falling on rather generic writing tropes.
He's an excellent designer with ideas he doesn't know how to clearly express.
The very definition of an auteur.
He's a great visionary and original storyteller but a weak writer.
And then 57 of you guys said he's kind of insane.
Now all of this seems to coalesce into a consensus
that he is a talented artist with a lot of really interesting original ideas.
But that he doesn't know when to stop and to delegate.
For instance, he has an original story idea,
but he insists on writing out the macro, and the micro story elements himself,
despite being objectively bad at writing dialogue.
And it's really too bad, because if Death Stranding were more lean,
it could have appealed to a lot more people, and it could have made a much bigger splash.
So, in closing, Death Stranding is an enigma.
It's a game that I'm glad that I played,
the one that's plagued with issues through and through.
And while I'm glad that Kojima got to pursue his passion project,
I do hope that his next attempt is far more coherent, more polished,
and much more fun.
But that's all from me.
Thank you so much for watching if you've made it all the way to this point.
You are a scholar and the Saint.
Special thank you again to the patrons that funded the production of this video.
Again, it would not have happened without the generosity of these individuals.
And a very special thank you to Zachary Johnson, Mike Holland,
Christopher Scott and Paige Richardson, for their generosity.
Let me know all of your thoughts on Death Stranding below.
And if you'd like to vote on and help fund the next critique,
make sure you go and check out my patreon page.
In addition to getting all sorts of behind-the-scenes peeks at the development of these critiques,
helping pick the thumbnails and much much more,
you also get access to exclusive monthly Q&As, free merchandise,
early access to these critiques before anybody else,
and exclusive videos just for patrons.
But thank you all for watching,
I love you all more than you could possibly know,
and I'll see you in the next video.